. >> GOOD AFTERNOON EVERYONE.
WELCOME TO THE JUNE 24TH 2025 REGULAR MEETING OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. >> MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL? THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN PRESENTS SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN PRESENT
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY PRESENT SUPERVISOR ENGARDIO
ENGARDIO PRESENTS SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER PRESENTS
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD PRESENT SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN
PRESENT MANDOLIN PRESENT SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR
PRESENT SUPERVISOR SADR SADR PRESENT SUPERVISOR CHERYL
SHERYL PRESENT AND SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON PRESENT MR.
PRESIDENT ALL MEMBERS ARE PRESENT.
>> THANK YOU MADAM CLERK THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT WE ARE ON THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL
HOMELAND OF THE RAMA ALONI WHO ARE THE ORIGINAL INHABITANTS OF
THE SAN FRANCISCO PENINSULA AS THE INDIGENOUS STEWARDS OF THIS
LAND AND IN ACCORDANCE WITH THEIR TRADITIONS THE RAW
MATERIALS MANY HAVE NEVER CEDED LOST NOR FORGOTTEN THEIR
RESPONSIBILITIES AS THE CARETAKERS OF THIS PLACE AS
WELL AS FOR ALL PEOPLES WHO RESIDE IN THEIR TRADITIONAL
TERRITORY AS GUESTS WE RECOGNIZE THAT WE BENEFIT FROM
LIVING AND WORKING ON THEIR TRADITIONAL HOMELAND.
WE WISH TO PAY OUR RESPECTS BY ACKNOWLEDGING THE ANCESTORS
ELDERS AND RELATIVES OF THE ROMITA ALONI COMMUNITY AND BY
AFFIRMING THEIR SOVEREIGN RIGHTS AS FIRST PEOPLES.
COLLEAGUES, WILL YOU JOIN ME IN RECITING THE PLEDGE OF
ALLEGIANCE THAT THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA STANDS?
>> ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD I WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE STAFF
AT S.F. GOV TV AND TODAY PARTICULARLY KALEENA MENDOZA.
THEY RECORD EACH OF OUR MEETINGS AND MAKE THE
TRANSCRIPTS AVAILABLE TO THE PUBLIC ONLINE.
MADAM CLERK, DO YOU HAVE ANY COMMUNICATIONS?
>> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS WELCOMES YOU ALL HERE TO ATTEND THIS MEETING
IN THE CHAMBER WHICH IS LOCATED WITHIN CITY HALL ON THE SECOND
FLOOR IN ROOM 250 WHERE YOU MAY WATCH THE PROCEEDING ON SGV
TV'S CHANNEL 26 OR VIEW THE LIVE STREAM AT W W W DOT S.F.
GOV'T TV.ORG. IF YOU'D LIKE TO SUBMIT YOUR
PUBLIC COMMENT IN WRITING YOU CAN SEND IT VIA EMAIL TO B O
S AT S.F. GEO V.ORG OR USE THE POSTAL SERVICE JUST ADDRESS
YOUR ENVELOPE TO THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
THE NUMBER ONE DR. CARLTON B GOOD PLACE CITY HALL ROOM 244
SAN FRANCISCO CALIFORNIA 94102. TO MAKE A REASONABLE
ACCOMMODATION REQUEST UNDER THE AMERICANS WITH DISABILITIES ACT
OR IF YOU NEED TO REQUEST LANGUAGE ASSISTANCE CONTACT THE
CLERK'S OFFICE AT LEAST TWO BUSINESS DAYS IN ADVANCE BY
CALLING (415) 554-5184. THANK YOU MEMBERS.
>> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
LET'S GO TO THE APPROVAL OF OUR MEETING MINUTES.
>> APPROVAL OF THE MAY 20TH 2025 BOARD MEETING MINUTES.
COLLEAGUES, I DON'T SEE ANYONE WITH CHANGES SO CAN I HAVE A
MOTION TO APPROVE THE MINUTES MOVED BY MAHMUD SECONDED BY
CHERYL. UH, MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU
PLEASE PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON EYES
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR CHEN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR RON GAUDIO
AND GAUDIO EYES SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR
MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN HI MANAGEMENT I
SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I AND SUPERVISOR SADR SADR EITHER
ARE LEBANESE ALL RIGHT WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MINUTES WILL BE
APPROVED AFTER PUBLIC COMMENT AS PRESENTED MADAM CLERK LET'S
GO TO THE CONSENT AGENDA ITEMS ONE THROUGH 12 ITEMS ONE
THROUGH 12 ARE ON CONSENT. >> THESE ITEMS ARE CONSIDERED
TO BE ROUTINE. IF A MEMBER OBJECTS AN ITEM MAY
BE REMOVED AND CONSIDERED SEPARATELY.
>> ALL RIGHTS. I DON'T THINK ANYONE WANTS TO
SEVER ANY OF THOSE SO MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON
ITEMS ONE THROUGH 12 SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES SUPERVISOR
WALTON WALTON EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN
CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR
AND ENGARDIO AND ENGARDIO EYES SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER EYES
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD EYES SUPERVISOR MANDEL MEN HIGH MAN
WOMAN EYES SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR EYE AND SUPERVISOR SADR
SADR EITHER ARE LEBANESE WITHOUT OBJECTION THESE
ORDINANCES ARE FINALLY PASSED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO
UNFINISHED BUSINESS PLEASE CALL ITEMS 13 AND 14 TOGETHER ITEM
13 AND 14 COMPRISE THE PROPOSED INTERIM BUDGETS FOR THE BUDGET
AND APPROPRIATION ORDINANCE AND THE INTERIM ANNUAL SALARY
ORDINANCE. ITEM 13 APPROPRIATES THE
ESTIMATED RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE
DEPARTMENTS AS OF MAY 30TH 2025 FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE
30TH 2026 AND JUNE 30TH 2027 AND ITEM 14 ENUMERATES
POSITIONS FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30TH 2026 AND JUNE
30TH 2027 TO CONTINUE TO CREATE OR ESTABLISH POSITIONS TO
ENUMERATE AND INCLUDE POSITIONS CREATED BY THE CHARTER OR STATE
LAW FOR WHICH COMPENSATION IS PAID FROM CITY AND COUNTY FUNDS
AND APPROPRIATED IN THE ANNUAL APPROPRIATION ORDINANCE AND TO
AUTHORIZE APPOINTMENTS OR CONTINUATION OF APPOINTMENTS TO
SPECIFY AND FIX THE COMPENSATION AND WORK SCHEDULES
THEREOF AND TO AUTHORIZE APPOINTMENTS AND FIXED
COMPENSATION TO TEMPORARY POSITIONS.
>> ALL RIGHT, LET'S TAKE THESE ITEMS SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE ORDINANCE ARE FINALLY PASSED.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 15.
>> ITEM 15. THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO
AUTHORIZE SETTLEMENT OF THE LAWSUIT FILED BY RIDGE GATE
APARTMENTS INC AGAINST THE CITY CONCERNING THE REAL PROPERTY
LOCATED AT 524 HOWARD STREET FOR A STIPULATED ASSESSED VALUE
OF THE SUBJECT PROPERTY FOR PROPERTY TAX PURPOSES OF
APPROXIMATELY 65 MILLION AS OF JANUARY 1ST 2021 OR IF THE
ASSESSMENT APPEALS BOARD DOES NOT ACCEPT THAT STIPULATED
ASSESSED VALUE AGREEMENT THAT THE ASSESSMENT APPEALS BOARD
WILL HOLD A NEW ASSESSMENT APPEAL HEARING TO DETERMINE THE
ASSESSED VALUE OF THE SUBJECT PROPERTY AS OF JANUARY 1ST,
2021 FOR THE FISCAL YEAR 2021 THROUGH 2022.
>> LET'S TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED.
>> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 16 ITEM 16 THIS IS A RESOLUTION
TO AUTHORIZE THE MAYOR'S OFFICE OF HOUSING AND COMMUNITY
DEVELOPMENT TO EXPEND SOUTH OF MARKET COMMUNITY STABILIZATION
FUND DOLLARS IN THE AMOUNT OF APPROXIMATELY 2.3 MILLION TO
ADDRESS VARIOUS IMPACTS OF DESTABILIZATION ON RESIDENTS
AND BUSINESSES IN THE SOMA JULY 1ST, 2025 THROUGH JUNE 30TH
2027 AGAIN SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 17.
>> ITEM 17 WAS REFERRED WITHOUT RECOMMENDATION FROM THE BUDGET
AND APPROPRIATIONS COMMITTEE A RESOLUTION TO APPROVE THE FIRST
AMENDMENT AND AUTHORIZE THE DIRECTOR OF PROPERTY ON BEHALF
OF THE DEPARTMENT OF HOMELESSNESS AND SUPPORT OF
HOUSING TO AMEND THE LEASE WITH LAWRENCE B STONE PROPERTIES
ZERO EIGHT LLC AS LANDLORD OF THE REAL PROPERTY LOCATED AT
2177 GERALD AVENUE FOR CONTINUED USE AS A TEMPORARY
SHELTER PROGRAM SUBMITTED UNDER CHAPTER 21 B OF THE
ADMINISTRATIVE CODE AS A CORE INITIATIVE LEASE TO AUTHORIZE
THE CITY'S CONTRIBUTION OF UP TO APPROXIMATELY 3 MILLION FOR
ADDITIONAL IMPROVEMENTS INCLUDING ANY PREDEVELOPMENT
COSTS INCURRED TO ADD APPROXIMATELY 82 SHELTER BEDS
AND A UTILITIES UPGRADE AT THE PROPERTY TO EXPAND THE
FOOTPRINT OF THE TEMPORARY SHELTER PROGRAM AND TO AFFIRM
THE SECOND DETERMINATION AND TO MAKE THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU SO
MUCH, PRESIDENT, MADAM AND COLLEAGUES, AS YOU KNOW
THIS ITEM WAS FORWARDED TO THE FULL BOARD FROM BUDGET
AND APPROPRIATIONS COMMITTEE WITHOUT RECOMMENDATION BUT I
HAVE HAD THE OPPORTUNITY TO MAKE CHANGES TO THIS RESOLUTION
WHICH WOULD HAVE EXPANDED THE JERALD COMMON SITE FROM 60 BEDS
AND NO FREE PARKING AND WOULD HAVE ADDED AN ADDITIONAL 82
BEDS AT THE SITE AND WOULD HAVE ALSO DRAMATICALLY INCREASED
COST AT THE SITE AT THE CONVERSATIONS WITH THE MAYOR'S
OFFICE, I'M HAPPY TO REPORT TODAY THAT WE WILL BE AMENDING
THIS RESOLUTION TO ONLY PROVIDE RESOURCES FOR A UTILITIES
UPGRADE AND ELIMINATE THE INCLUSION AND EXPANSION OF 82
ADDITIONAL BEDS AT THE SITE. >> THE MAYOR HAS AGREED TO WORK
WITH COMMUNITY AND OUR OFFICE TO EXPLORE WHAT WILL BE BEST AT
THE SITE AND WITH INCLUSION OF COMMUNITY VOICE.
>> I WANT TO THANK MY ENTIRE DISTRICT AND TEAM TRACY,
LINDSEY, NATALIE AND PERCY FOR KEEPING ME LEVELHEADED DURING
THESE DISCUSSIONS MY COLLEAGUES ON THE BUDGET
AND APPROPRIATIONS COMMITTEE, THE MAYOR'S OFFICE AND OF
COURSE OUR BUDGET CHAIR SUPERVISOR CHAN FOR WORKING ON
THIS AS WELL. THE MAIN THING THAT I HAVE
ALWAYS MAINTAINED IS THAT THE BEST OUTCOMES COME FROM
INCLUDING COMMUNITY VOICE WHEN MAKING DECISIONS.
WITH THAT I'M GOING TO READ AND TO RECORD THE AMENDMENTS
WHICH I HAVE DISTRIBUTED TO ALL OF YOU AT THE START OF THIS
MEETING PAGE LINE PAGE ONE LINE TWO AT 1,246,746 AND STRIKE
3,055,982 PAGE ONE LINE EIGHT ADD 1,000,200 AND 46,746
AND STRIKE 3,055,980 TO PAGE ONE LINE NINE STRIKE TWO AT
PAGE ONE LINE TEN STRIKE THE ENTIRE LINE APPROXIMATELY 82
SHELTER BEDS THROUGH A DORM BUILD OUT TO AN EXISTING
BUILDING ON THE PAGE ONE LINE 11 STRIKE PROPERTY AND AT FOUR
STRIKE TO SUPPORT THE EXPANDED FOOTPRINT.
PAGE ONE LINE 12 STRIKE OF THE TEMPORARY SHELTER PROGRAM PAGE
THREE LINE 12 STRIKE TO INITIATE PHASE TWO OF THE
PROGRAM THROUGH PAGE THREE LINE 14 STRIKE AS THE CITY WOULD
PAGE THREE, LINE 15 STRIKE THE ENTIRE LINE AND AN ADDITIONAL
82 SHELTER BEDS THROUGH A DORM BUILT OUT OF EXISTING BUILDING
ON THE PAGE THREE LINE 16 STRIKE PROPERTY INTO A
CONGREGATE DORMITORY AND ADD TO ADD ELECTRICAL AND ADD BETTER
PAGE THREE LINE 17 AT EXISTING FACILITIES STRIKE EXPAND THE
FOOTPRINT OF THE PROGRAM AND STRIKE UNDER THE PAGE THREE
LINE 18 STRIKE TERMS OF THE FIRST AMENDMENT PAGE FOR LINE
TWO AT 1,246,746 STRIKE 3,055,982 PAGE FOUR LINE SEVEN
AT 1,246,746 STRIKE 3,055,082 AND PAGE SIX LINE TWO AT
1,246,746 AND STRIKE 3,055,982 AND I WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT
THESE AMENDMENTS ARE NOT SUBSTANTIVE OR LET'S HEAR FROM
THE CITY ATTORNEY DEPUTY CITY ATTORNEY BRAD REST.
YES, THESE AMENDMENTS ARE NOT SUBSTANTIVE AND THE BOARD CAN
ADOPT THEM TODAY AND MOVE THE ITEM FORWARD.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH. AND SO I WOULD LIKE TO MOVE
THAT WE MOVE THIS ITEM FORWARD WITH THE AMENDMENTS.
A MOTION HAS BEEN MADE BY A SUPERVISOR WELL, IT HAS BEEN
SECONDED BY SUPERVISOR CHAN. I WOULD LIKE TO CONGRATULATE
SUPERVISOR WALTON AND THE DISTRICT TEN TEAM AND TO THANK
YOU ALSO TO THANK OUR BUDGET AND APPROPRIATIONS CHAIR
SUPERVISOR CHAN FOR ALL OF YOUR WORK ON THIS ALSO TO THANK THE
MAYOR'S OFFICE AND OUR BOARD LIAISON ADAM TALKS ABOUT BUT
ALSO KUNAL MODY AND H. S H SHEREEN MCSPADDEN AND HER
TEAM AND THE CITY ATTORNEY AND OF COURSE THE CITY ATTORNEY
AND I THINK THIS IS A VERY HAPPY DEVELOPMENT.
>> SO WITH THAT I THINK I CAN TAKE THAT MOTION WITHOUT
OBJECTION FOLKS. >> YES.
AND THEN ON THE AMENDED ITEM I THINK WE CAN TAKE THAT SAME
HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS
ADOPTED. >> ALL RIGHT, MADAM CLERK,
PLEASE CALL ITEMS 18 AND 19 TOGETHER ITEM 18 AND 19 ARE TWO
RESOLUTIONS THAT DETERMINE IF LIQUOR LICENSES ISSUED WILL
SERVE THE PUBLIC CONVENIENCE ITEM 18 IT DETERMINES THAT A
TYPE 90 ON SALE GENERAL MUSIC VENUE LIQUOR LICENSE TO
BERGAMOT OIL LLC DOING BUSINESS AS CLUB DELUXE LOCATED AT 1511
HAIGHT STREET AND FOR ITEM 19 DETERMINING THAT THE PERSON TO
PERSON PREMISE TO PREMISE TRANSFER OVER TIME 21 OFF SALE
GENERAL BEER WINE AND DISTILLED SPIRITS LIQUOR LICENSE TO
BOTTLES AND BITES LLC DOING BUSINESS AS BOTTLES AND BITES
LOCATED AT 1799 UNION STREET WILL BOTH SERVE THE PUBLIC
CONVENIENCE AND TO REQUEST THAT THE CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF
ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGE CONTROL IMPOSE CONDITIONS ON THE
ISSUANCE OF BOTH LICENSES AND WE TAKE THESE ITEMS SAME
HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE
ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM
20. ITEM 20 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO
ENDORSE THE TCAP. THE TENDERLOIN COMMUNITY ACTION
PLAN INVESTMENT BLUEPRINT AS THE COMMUNITY LED STRATEGY TO
SUPPORT EQUITABLE RECOVERY AND REVITALIZATION IN THE
TENDERLOIN AND TO ENCOURAGE CITY DEPARTMENTS, PHILANTHROPIC
AND PRIVATE SECTOR PARTNERS TO USE THE TCAP INVESTMENT
BLUEPRINT AS A GUIDING FRAMEWORK TO COORDINATE FUTURE
INVESTMENTS IN THE TENDERLOIN. >> WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM SAME
HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS
ADOPTED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 21 ITEM 21 THIS IS AN
ORDINANCE TO APPROVE THE SURVEILLANCE TECHNOLOGY POLICY
FOR THE MUNICIPAL TRANSPORTATION AGENCIES
CONTINUED USE OF EXISTING AUTOMATED RED LIGHT AND NO TURN
ENFORCEMENT CAMERAS AND AGAIN SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING
MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 22.
>> ITEM 22 THIS IS A MOTION TO REAPPOINT LAURA THOMAS TO THE
ENTERTAINMENT COMMISSION FOR A TERM ENDING JULY 1ST, 2029 SAME
HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTION IS
APPROVED MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 23 ITEM 23 THIS IS A
MOTION TO CONFIRM THE APPOINTMENT OF PRATIBHA TEKI TO
THE POLICE COMMISSION TERM ENDING APRIL 30TH 2029 AND I
THINK WE CAN TAKE THE SAME HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE MOTION IS APPROVED MADAM CLERK PLEASE
CALL ITEM 24 ITEM 24 MOTION TO APPROVE PRESIDENT RAFAEL MANDAL
MINH'S NOMINATION OF THE SUPERVISOR OF SUPERVISOR
AND CHERYL AS AN ALTERNATE TO SEATS 1 TO 3 TERMS ENDING JUNE
6TH, 2027 TO THE ENHANCED INFRASTRUCTURE FINANCING
DISTRICT PUBLIC FINANCING AUTHORITY NUMBER ONE.
>> COLLEAGUES, CAN I HAVE A MOTION TO EXCUSE SUPERVISOR
CHERYL FROM THE VOTE MOVED BY SUPERVISOR MELGAR AND SECONDED
BY SUPERVISOR SAUDER WITHOUT OBJECTION THE SUPERVISOR CHERYL
IS EXCUSED. MADAME CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON THE MOTION TO EXCUSED SUPERVISOR CHERYL FROM
ITEM 24 SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN
CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY
EYES SUPERVISOR AND ENGARDIO AND ENGARDIO EYES SUPERVISOR
FIELDER FIELDER EYES SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR
RANDLEMAN MANAGEMENT I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I
AND SUPERVISOR SAUDER SADR I EITHER ATTORNEYS I THINK WE
EXCUSED SUPERVISOR CHERYL TWICE BUT WE WILL HE IS EXCUSED
AND THEN I THINK WE CAN TAKE THE MOTION SAME HOUSE, SAME
CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTION IS APPROVED MADAM CLERK
I'LL LET'S GO TO ROLL CALL FIRST UP TO INTRODUCE NEW
BUSINESS IS SUPERVISOR CHERYL GIVE YOU A LITTLE TIME TO GET
BACK TO YOUR DESK TO SUBMIT SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR WALTON SUBMIT.
THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHAN SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR CHEN SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU
MADAM CLERK COLLEAGUES I AM TODAY ANNOUNCING A LEGISLATIVE
DRAFTING REQUEST TO ESTABLISH THE SAN FRANCISCO HATE CRIME
REWARD FUND WHICH WOULD AUTHORIZE THE CHIEF OF POLICE
IN COORDINATION WITH THE DISTRICT ATTORNEY TO OFFER
INFORMANTS A REWARD OF UP TO $100,000 FOR INFORMATION
LEADING TO THE CONVICTION OF A HATE CRIME PERPETRATOR.
THIS PROPOSAL COMES AFTER A SPATE OF HIGH PROFILE INCIDENTS
OVER THE LAST YEAR THAT HAVE BEEN INVESTIGATED AND IN SOME
CASES PROSECUTED AS HATE CRIMES IN SAN FRANCISCO.
EARLY IN MY CAREER I WORKED WITH THEN DISTRICT ATTORNEY
ARLO SMITH TO ESTABLISH THE DA'S HATE CRIMES TASK FORCE
WHICH DEVELOPED POLICIES AND PROTOCOLS FOR PROSECUTING
THESE CRIMES AT A TIME WHEN CALIFORNIA HAD ONLY JUST
ENACTED ITS HATE CRIME STATUTE .
MUCH LATER IN MY CAREER I WORKED AS A CIVILIAN MEMBER OF
THE POLICE DEPARTMENT COMMAND STAFF A TWO YEAR STINT DURING
COVID 19 IN WHICH SAN FRANCISCO WITNESSED A SIX FOLD INCREASE
IN HATE CRIMES DIRECTED AGAINST OUR AAPI COMMUNITY.
HATE CRIMES ARE DEFINED BY A BIAS MOTIVATION THAT ENHANCES
THE SERIOUSNESS OF EXISTING CRIMES WHICH CAN RANGE FROM
GRAFFITI VANDALISM TO SERIOUS AND EVEN VIOLENT FELONIES UP TO
AND INCLUDING HOMICIDES. SO I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT THAT
OUR HATE CRIME REWARD FUND OFFER FLEXIBILITY OF UP TO
$100,000 TO ACCOUNT FOR THE WIDE RANGE OF POSSIBLY
APPLICABLE CRIMES. ONE FEATURE OF HATE CRIMES
THAT'S IMPORTANT TO RECOGNIZE IS THAT IT IS RARELY THE AIM OF
A PERPETRATOR TO VICTIMIZE ANY ONE INDIVIDUAL OR BUSINESS
SOLELY BUT RATHER TO INSTILL FEAR IN ENTIRE COMMUNITIES.
WE HAVE SEEN THAT IN MANY COMMUNITIES HERE IN SAN
FRANCISCO OVER THE LAST YEAR A JEWISH BUSINESS
AND ANTI-SEMITIC ATTACK IN RECENT WEEKS STILL ANOTHER
ATTACK ON AN AAPI SENIOR LAST MONTH THREATS AGAINST OUR TRANS
COMMUNITY AND LGBTQ PLUS COMMUNITY MORE GENERALLY AN
ANTI-MUSLIM VANDALISM AND HARASSMENT AT LOCAL MOSQUES
LAST YEAR AS A CITY ENRICHED AS OURS IS BY ITS DIVERSITY
AND COMMITTED TO PLURALISM AS SAN FRANCISCO IS, WE SHOULD
LEAD ON THESE ISSUES. IN MY VIEW A GENEROUSLY FUNDED
HATE CRIME REWARD FUND WILL HELP TO FLIP THE SCRIPT ON
LAWLESS BIGOTS BY INSTILLING FEAR INTO HATE CRIMINALS THAT
INFORMANTS WILL BE WELL PAID TO BRING THEM TO JUSTICE FOR THEIR
HATEFUL VANDALISM AND VIOLENCE ESPECIALLY IN TIMES LIKE THESE
. IT'S WHY IT'S VITAL THAT WE
TAKE THESE ATTACKS SERIOUSLY. THIS REWARD FUND THAT I'M
PROPOSING WILL SEND A STRONG MESSAGE TO WOULD BE HATE
CRIMINALS IN SAN FRANCISCO THAT OUR CITY IS DOING EXACTLY THAT.
I WANT TO THANK COMPTROLLER GREG WAGNER AND HIS OFFICE WITH
WHOM I'M WORKING ON OPTIONS FOR STRUCTURING AND FUNDING THIS
FUND. WHICH MAY EXPAND ON SPEEDY'S
EXISTING REWARD FUND WHICH IS RIGHT NOW LIMITED TO HOMICIDE
CASES. IN EITHER CASE IT WOULD BE AN
SFPD FUNDED FUND AND THE LEGISLATION WOULD ENSURE THAT
IT'S OPEN TO PHILANTHROPIC SUPPORT.
I ALSO WANT TO THANK MY EARLY CO-SPONSORS SUPERVISOR SHERYL
SADR, MAHMUD AND GUARDIAN AND CHEN.
AS ALWAYS, I WELCOME THE OPPORTUNITY TO COLLABORATE WITH
OTHERS AS THIS LEGISLATION MOVES FORWARD AND THE REST I
SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR DORSEY
SUPERVISOR AND GAUDIO SUBMIT THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR FIELDER SUBMIT. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD SUBMIT THANK YOU.
>> SUPERVISOR AMENDMENT I HAVE A BRIEF INTRODUCTION.
>> COLLEAGUES TODAY I AM INTRODUCING LEGISLATION THAT
BUILDS ON OUR CITY'S ALL ELECTRIC NEW CONSTRUCTION
ORDINANCE WHICH THE BOARD PASSED IN NOVEMBER OF 2020.
THAT ORDINANCE GENERALLY PROHIBITS NEW CONSTRUCTION
PROJECTS FROM INSTALLING GAS PIPING AND APPLIANCES WITH
SPECIFIED EXCEPTIONS. THE LEGISLATION I AM
INTRODUCING TODAY WILL EXPAND THE ALL ELECTRIC ORDINANCE TO
NOW INCLUDE MAJOR RENOVATIONS THAT IS ALTERATIONS
AND ADDITIONS TO EXISTING BUILDINGS THAT INCLUDE
SUBSTANTIAL UPGRADES TO MECHANICAL SYSTEMS
AND STRUCTURES. I WANT TO THANK SUPERVISORS
MAHMOOD AND FIELDER FOR THEIR EARLY CO-SPONSORSHIP.
AND I WANT TO THANK TYRONE JOO, CHARLES SHEEHAN, CINDY
CRAWFORD, BARRY HOOPER, JOSEPH V.S. NELLIS HER FOR MASSIVE
ENVIRONMENT FOR ALL OF THEIR WORK AS WELL AS ROB COPPOLA
FROM THE CITY ATTORNEY'S OFFICE AND CALVIN AND BRAD PHELPS
FROM MY OFFICE. >> AND THE REST I SUBMIT.
THANK YOU MR. PRESIDENT. SUPERVISOR MELGAR SUBMIT THANK
YOU AND SUPERVISOR SARTOR I DO SO LEGISLATION ALONGSIDE
MAYOR LURIE TO ADVANCE THE 530 SANSOM PROJECT A MAJOR DOWNTOWN
DEVELOPMENT THAT WILL BRING COUNTLESS NEIGHBORHOOD
BENEFITS. THIS REPRESENTS THE MOST
AMBITIOUS NEW DEVELOPMENT IN THE NORTHERN PART OF
DOWNTOWN IN DECADES. A 41 STOREY TOWER WILL RISE
COMPRISING MIXED USES ACROSS HOTEL OFFICE, RESTAURANT
AND WHEAT RETAIL. AND WHEN COMPLETED IT WILL
GENERATE MORE THAN $800 MILLION IN ANNUAL ECONOMIC ACTIVITY.
>> THIS PROJECT MAKES IT CLEAR THAT OUR DOWNTOWN RECOVERY IS
REAL AND QUICKLY ACCELERATING. BUT I'M ALSO EXCITED ABOUT THIS
PROJECT FOR ALL THE NEIGHBORHOOD BENEFITS IT WILL
BRING ABOUT. FIRST IT WILL DELIVER A NEW
STATE OF THE ART FIRE STATION 13 TO SUPPORT OUR FIRE
DEPARTMENT AS THEY SERVE PARTS OF CHINATOWN FINANCIAL DISTRICT
EMBARCADERO, BARBARY COAST TELEGRAPH HILL AND JACKSON
SQUARE. ADDITIONALLY, THE PROJECT WILL
GENERATE NEARLY $15 MILLION IN AFFORDABLE HOUSING
CONTRIBUTIONS TO THE CITY TO SUPPORT THE CREATION OF A 100%
AFFORDABLE SENIOR HOUSING AT 77 TWO PACIFIC AVENUE IN CHINATOWN
OR OTHER DEVELOPMENTS WITHIN DISTRICT THREE.
AND THIS IS MONEY WE WILL SEE QUICKLY WITH AN INITIAL $2
MILLION PAID WITHIN SIX MONTHS OF THE ENTITLEMENT.
AND FINALLY, AS WE FACE REAL FISCAL CHALLENGES, WE SHOULD BE
EXCITED ABOUT THE $14 MILLION IN ANNUAL GENERAL FUND REVENUE
THAT THIS PROJECT WILL CONTRIBUTE.
AND THIS SHOULD BE A REMINDER THAT WE CAN MEET OUR BUDGET
CHALLENGES THROUGH GROWTH AS WELL AS THROUGH SAVINGS.
>> I ALSO WANT TO RECOGNIZE THE HEAVY LIFTING THAT MY
PREDECESSOR AARON PESKIN DID OVER THE PAST DECADE TO MOVE
THIS PROJECT FORWARD FROM A VISION TO NOW BEING ON THE CUSP
OF GROUNDBREAKING. >> THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
INCLUDING MANY OF MY CURRENT COLLEAGUES ENDORSED THIS
PROJECT IN A RESOLUTION PASSED IN NOVEMBER 2024 WITH AN 11 TO
0 VOTE. THIS PROJECT ALSO HAS
WIDESPREAD SUPPORT FROM LABOR WHO RECOGNIZE THE TREMENDOUS
NUMBER OF GOOD PAYING JOBS THAT WILL GO INTO THE CONSTRUCTION
AND MAINTENANCE OF THIS PROJECT.
I'M VERY HAPPY TO SEE THIS PROJECT MOVING FORWARD IN MY
DISTRICT. AFTER A PLANNING COMMISSION
HEARING IN JULY. I LOOK FORWARD TO THIS
LEGISLATION COMING TO THE BOARD FOR CONSIDERATION LATER IN THE
SUMMER. I HOPE IT WILL EARN YOUR
SUPPORT SO THAT WE CAN GET SHOVELS IN THE GROUND.
A NEW FIRE STATION BUILT AND AFFORDABLE HOUSING FUNDS
DISTRIBUTED AND THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR SARTOR.
>> MR. PRESIDENT. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
>> LET'S GO TO OUR 2:30 P.M. SPECIAL ORDER RECOGNITION OF
COMMENDATIONS. IT'S NOW TIME TO RECOGNIZE
COMMENDATIONS FOR MERITORIOUS SERVICE TO THE CITY AND COUNTY
OF SAN FRANCISCO. >> AND WE WILL START TODAY WITH
DISTRICT TWO SUPERVISOR CHERYL COLLEAGUES.
TODAY IS THE LAST BOARD MEETING OF PRIDE MONTH.
>> AND TODAY I AM SO HONORED TO COMMEND HARRY BRO.
HARRY, WOULD YOU PLEASE COME JOIN US UP HERE?
>> HARRY FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO HAVE NOT HAD THE PLEASURE TO
MEET HIM IS AN EXTRAORDINARY SAN FRANCISCAN WHOSE LIFE HAS
BEEN DEFINED BY RESILIENCE, BY CREATIVITY, BY SERVICE AND MOST
OF ALL BY COMPASSION. HARRY MOVED TO SAN FRANCISCO
IN 1970. >> CURRENTLY LIVES IN CATHEDRAL
HILL AND HE IS DISTRICT TWO'S REPRESENTATIVE ON THE
DEPARTMENT OF DISABILITY AND AGING SERVICES ADVISORY
COUNCIL. >> BORN AND RAISED IN A SMALL
TOWN OF LOUISIANA QUITE CLOSE TO WHERE MANY OF MY FAMILY
COMES FROM. >> HARRY BROUGHT WITH HIM A
QUIET STRENGTH AND A FIERCE SENSE OF JUSTICE THAT WOULD
COME TO DEFINE HIS ROLE IN SAN FRANCISCO'S LGBTQ PLUS
COMMUNITY. AFTER TESTING POSITIVE FOR HIV
IN THE EARLY 1980S DURING THE HARROWING EARLY YEARS OF THE
AIDS EPIDEMIC, HARRY THREW HIMSELF INTO THE VOLUNTEERING
COMMUNITY AS A POWERFUL ADVOCATE AND FRIEND FOR OTHERS
NEGOTIATE NAVIGATING THE LONG ROAD OF SURVIVAL.
>> SINCE THEN HARRY HAS VOLUNTEERED WITH THE SHANTI
PROJECT S.F. AIDS FOUNDATION, THE SENIOR IN DISABILITY ACTION
AND MANY MANY MORE HELPING PROVIDE EMOTIONAL AND PRACTICAL
SUPPORT TO OUR DISABLED RESIDENTS AS WELL AS AIDS
SURVIVORS. >> HARRY IS NOT JUST A WITNESS
TO HISTORY BUT HE'S A SHAPER OF IT SHOWING UP FOR HIS COMMUNITY
AS AN ACTIVIST AND AN ARTIST. >> HE IS DEDICATED TO CARRYING
ON THE MEMORY OF THE FRIENDS HE LOST IN THE EPIDEMIC.
SHARING THEIR STORIES TO ENSURE THEY ARE NEVER FORGOTTEN.
AND IF YOU KNOW HARRY, YOU KNOW THAT HE DOES ALL THIS WITH
REMARKABLE HUMILITY. MOST RECENTLY HE SPEARHEADED
THE CREATION OF THE LARGE SCALE PRIDE FLAG MURAL AT THE JANE
WARNER PLAZA IN THE CASTRO OF VIBRANT AND LASTING TRIBUTE TO
THE LGBTQ PLUS COMMUNITY'S VISIBILITY AND RESILIENCE.
AS OUR REPRESENTATIVE ON THE DHS ADVISORY COUNCIL, HE
CONTINUES TO LIFT UP THE VOICES OF COMMUNITY MEMBERS WHO ARE
TOO OFTEN OVERLOOKED WHETHER IT'S MENTORING OTHERS,
ADVOCATING FOR SERVICES OR MARCHING DOWN MARKET STREET
DRESSED IN FULL ROCKY HORROR FOR PRIDE.
>> HARRY EMBODIES WHAT IT MEANS TO LIVE BOLDLY AND GIVE BACK.
HIS STORY REMINDS US THAT PRIDE IS NOT ONLY ABOUT CELEBRATION.
IT'S ABOUT REMEMBRANCE, VISIBILITY AND HONORING THOSE
WHO PAVED THE WAY. >> WE ARE GRATEFUL TODAY AND I
AM ALWAYS GRATEFUL FOR HARRY BRO AND FOR HIS LIFETIME OF
SERVICE. STRENGTH AND SPIRIT AND WE ARE
INCREDIBLY PROUD TO CELEBRATE HIM THIS PRIDE MONTH.
BUT FOR ME PERSONALLY HARRY IS A CONSTANT REMINDER THAT
SUCCESS AND PASSION AND A LIFE OF COMMITMENT TO FRIENDS IS NOT
ALWAYS A LINEAR JOURNEY. >> YOU ARE AN INSPIRING
REMINDER TO ME PERSONALLY THAT SOMETIMES WE MAY FALL
AND SOMETIMES WE MAY DOUBT BUT THAT ONLY GIVES US MORE
STRENGTH. >> AND THAT SUCCESS AND A
BETTER LIFE ONLY COMES THROUGH SOME HARDSHIP AND EVERY DOWN IS
JUST A WEIGHT ON THE STEP TOWARDS MORE UPS.
AND YOU PERSONALLY HAVE INSPIRED ME TO KEEP PUSHING
FORWARD AS I KNOW YOU'VE INSPIRED SO MANY OTHERS.
SO HARRY, I WANT TO THANK YOU QUITE FRANKLY FOR BEING YOU.
I'M SO GRATEFUL TO KNOW YOU JUST A LITTLE BIT THAT I DO.
AND I KNOW THAT MY THANKS IS SHOWN BY SO MANY OTHERS HERE
IN SAN FRANCISCO. HARRY, THANK YOU.
I WANT TO THANK YOU. IT'S A VERY MOVING THING TO BE
HONORED. AND I WANT TO THANK SAN
FRANCISCO FOR WHAT IT'S GIVEN ME IN THE LAST 50, 60 YEARS.
AND I ALSO WANT TO POINT OUT THAT WE'RE UNDER WHAT I
CONSIDER TO BE DURESS IN THIS COUNTRY RIGHT NOW FOR THE LGBT
COMMUNITY. AND I WANT TO BE GRATEFUL FOR
ANYTHING THAT THIS BOARD CAN DO TO CONTINUE TO SUPPORT THE LGBT
COMMUNITY IN THIS CITY AND IN THE WORLD BY OUR EXAMPLE.
I'M VERY GRATEFUL. AND I WASN'T PREPARED TO MAKE
ANY SPEECH SO KIND OF FUMBLING .
>> BUT SAN FRANCISCO IS THE BEACON IN THIS COUNTRY FOR
TREATING PEOPLE THE WAY THEY SHOULD BE TREATED, FOR TREATING
EACH OTHER WITH HUMILITY AND COMPASSION.
AND SYMPATHY AND EMPATHY. AND IF WE DON'T CONTINUE TO DO
THAT, THE COUNTRY'S GOING TO SUFFER.
BECAUSE I KNOW FROM THE WAY THAT I PUT THAT MURAL IN JANE
WARNER PLAZA PRIMARILY BECAUSE IT IS ON A WORLDWIDE WEB CAMERA
THAT CAN BE SEEN 24 SEVEN AND DELIVER THE MESSAGE THAT
THE CASTRO AND SAN FRANCISCO IS OPEN TO ALL PEOPLE NO MATTER
WHAT THEIR GENDER OR THEIR NEEDS OR ANY OF THE REST OF IT.
ANYBODY CAN COME TO SAN FRANCISCO AND BE CARED FOR AS A
HUMAN BEING AND TREATED WELL. AND I HOPE THAT THAT CONTINUES
LONG AFTER I'M NO LONGER AROUND WHICH BEING 80 YEARS OLD THERE
IS A LIMIT AND I REALIZE IT SO FOR THE REST OF MY TIME I WILL
BE FIGHTING FOR THOSE PRINCIPLES THAT SAN FRANCISCO
AND THE CITY THAT'S NAMED FOR SAINT FRANCIS WILL ENGENDER.
THANK YOU ALL FOR YOUR SUPPORT IN THAT AND YOUR CONTINUED WORK
TOWARD THOSE GOALS. DISTRICT FIVE SUPERVISOR
MAHMOOD CAN WE HAVE MR. MINISTER MARVIN WHITE TO COME
TO THE PODIUM? >> COLLEAGUES TODAY I HAVE THE
PROFOUND HONOR OF RECOGNIZING A VISIONARY ARTIST, A SPIRITUAL
LEADER AND TRUTH TELLER WHOSE WORK HAS RESHAPED HOW WE
UNDERSTAND FAITH JUSTICE AND JOY HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
>> WE ARE HERE TO CELEBRATE MINISTER MARVIN K WHITE, THE
MINISTER OF CELEBRATION AT GLIDE MEMORIAL CHURCH WHOSE
MINISTRY IS AS ROOTED IN POETRY AS IT IS IN PROPHETIC POWER
AND WHOSE LEADERSHIP SPEAKS NOT JUST TO THE SOUL OF A
CONGREGATION BUT TO THE SOUL OF OUR CITY.
>> HE'S A PUBLIC THEOLOGIAN, A PREACHER AND A POET WHO BRINGS
PEOPLE TOGETHER ACROSS PERCEIVED BOUNDARIES OF RACE,
SEXUALITY, GENDER, FAITH AND IDENTITY AND INVITES US
INTO A MORE LOVING, LIBERATED AND UNIFIED FUTURE.
>> WHEN I FIRST ASKED AROUND ABOUT MINISTER MARVIN, I
EXPECTED TO HEAR ABOUT HIS WORK AT GLIDE, HIS SERMONS OR HIS
ART. >> AND I DID.
>> BUT WHAT I HEARD MOST CLEARLY OVER AND OVER AGAIN WAS
MORE IMPORTANTLY HOW HE MAKES PEOPLE FEEL.
>> PEOPLE SAID HE GIVES ME PERMISSION TO FEEL JOY AGAIN.
>> HE HELPS US GRIEVE HONESTLY AND CELEBRATE FIERCELY.
>> HE REMINDS US THAT GOD IS NOT DONE WITH US YET WHETHER ON
THE STAGE BEHIND A PULPIT OR HOLDING SPACE FOR HEALING.
MINISTER MARVIN BRINGS PEOPLE INTO A DEEPER RELATIONSHIP WITH
THEMSELVES WITH ONE ANOTHER AND WITH A HIGHER CALLING
TOWARDS JUSTICE MINISTER MARVIN EARNED HIS MASTER OF DIVINITY
FROM THE PULPIT THE PACIFIC SCHOOL OF RELIGION IN BERKELEY.
I WILL NOT HOLD IT AGAINST YOU AS SOMEONE FROM THE OTHER
SCHOOL AND HE'S NEVER STOPPED CREATING SENSE.
HE IS THE AUTHOR OF FOUR BOOKS OF POETRY INCLUDING OUR NAME BE
WITNESS STATUS AND TWO LAMBDA LITERARY AWARD NOMINATED
COLLECTIONS. LAST RITES AND NOTHING UGLY
FLY. >> HIS WORDS HAVE BEEN
PERFORMED ON STAGES ACROSS THE COUNTRY AND ADAPTED FOR SCREEN
AND HE HIMSELF HAS TOURED NATIONALLY AND INTERNATIONALLY
AS A MEMBER OF THE GROUNDBREAKING PERFORMANCE
COLLECTIVE POMO AFRO HOMOS ONE OF THE EARLIEST GROUPS
CENTERING BLACK NARRATIVES ONSTAGE.
>> HE HAS LED WRITING WORKSHOPS IN CLASSROOMS, PRISONS
AND CHURCHES. HE IS A CAVE CANHAM FELLOW
AND HE HELPED FOUND TWO VITAL SPACES FOR AND BIPOC WRITERS.
FIRE AND INK AND BIG GLAM. IN 2019 HE WAS NAMED ONE OF THE
WHY BECAME 100 FOR HIS CULTURAL AND COMMUNITY IMPACT BUT HIS
ARTISTRY IS NOT SEPARATE FROM HIS MINISTRY AT GLIDE
AND THROUGHOUT HIS LIFE HE HAS USED STORYTELLING AS SALVATION
AND IMAGINATION AS RESISTANCE. >> WHEN REVEREND CECIL WILLIAMS
SELECTED MINISTER MARVIN TO SERVE GLIDE, HE DIDN'T JUST
CHOOSE A SUCCESSOR. >> HE CHOSE A PATH FORWARD.
>> MINISTER MARVIN LEADS WITH CELEBRATION BUT HE'S NOT AFRAID
OF GRIEF. >> HE LEADS WITH LAUGHTER BUT
HE DOES NOT IGNORE PAIN. >> AND ABOVE ALL HE LEADS WITH
LOVE. RADICAL, ALL INCLUSIVE EMBODIED
LOVE IN A WORLD WHERE SO MANY AND TRANS PEOPLE HAVE BEEN TOLD
THAT FAITH DOES NOT BELONG TO THEM.
MINISTER MARTIN MARVIN HAS REWRITTEN THAT SCRIPT.
>> HE HAS REMINDED US THAT THE DIVINE CAN BE FOUND IN A POEM
AND A PROTEST AND IN EACH OTHER .
>> HIS LEADERSHIP DURING PRIDE MONTH AND JUNETEENTH IS NOT
INCIDENTAL. >> IT IS ESSENTIAL HE SHOWS US
WHAT LIBERATION CAN LOOK LIKE WHEN ROOTED IN HISTORY
ACCEPTANCE AND LOOKING FORWARD .
>> MR. MARVIN IS WHAT WE IN DISTRICT FIVE CALL A LIGHT
AND WHAT WE IN THE TENDERLOIN AS A RESIDENT CALL A LIGHT AS
WELL NOT A SPOTLIGHT BUT A LANTERN SOMETHING YOU CAN CARRY
WITH YOU SOMETHING THAT HELPS YOU SEE MORE CLEARLY
IN SOMETHING THAT CALLS YOU HOME.
>> HE IS PART OF A LINEAGE OF BLACK FAITH LEADERS WHO HAVE
TO REDEFINE WHAT THE CHURCH CAN BE NOT JUST AS A SANCTUARY BUT
A STAGE AS A SCHOOL AND A SITE OF RESISTANCE.
>> HE'S NOT ONLY BUILDING A SPIRITUAL LEGACY.
HE'S BUILDING A SPACE FOR HEALING FOR ART, FOR PRESENCE
AND FOR ENDLESS POSSIBILITY. >> SO COLLEAGUES, PLEASE JOIN
ME IN RECOGNIZING MINISTER MARVIN KAYE WHITE FOR HIS
VISIONARY LEADERSHIP. >> THE BOARD NEVER GETS THAT
APPLAUSE. >> UNAPOLOGETIC JOY HIS
ENDURING MINISTRY AND HIS ABILITY TO SEE HOLINESS
AND PLACES THE WORLD TOO OFTEN OVERLOOKS.
>> MINISTER MARVIN, THANK YOU FOR SHOWING US THAT CELEBRATION
CAN BE SACRED, THAT POETRY CAN BE PROPHETIC AND THE COMMUNITY
CAN BE A CHURCH. >> ON BEHALF OF THE PEOPLE OF
DISTRICT FIVE, THE TENDERLOIN AND THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN
FRANCISCO, WE ARE PROUD TO HONOR YOU TODAY.
>> WE YOU GUYS WILL APPRECIATE THIS.
>> THERE'S A TWO MINUTE TIME CLOCK RIGHT HERE AND AND I'M A
BLACK GAY PREACHER. >> THANK YOU.
IT IS AN HONOR AND A PRIVILEGE TO BE A RESIDENT OF DISTRICT
FIVE TO WORK IN DISTRICT FIVE TO KNOW THE STREETS OF THE
TENDERLOIN INTIMATELY, TO WALK THEM EVERY DAY THREE TIMES A
DAY WITH MY 150 POUND DOG AND TO KNOW THAT THERE IS
MINISTRY IN THE TENDERLOIN JUST BY WALKING AMONGST THE PEOPLE
AND LEARNING TO FIND THE BEAUTY AND TO AND TO KNOW YOUR WAY
HOME BY THE PEOPLE WHETHER THEY'RE POSTED ON THE CORNER OR
STANDING IN LINE FOR FOOD AT GLIDE.
IT IS AN HONOR TO BE HERE AT THIS POINT IN MY MR. WHITE CAN
YOU PLEASE SPEAK DIRECTLY INTO THE MICROPHONE SO WE CAN BEST
HEAR YOU? >> YES, MA'AM.
THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
I WANT TO SAY THAT I STAND HERE IN THE LONG SHADOW OF THE LATE
GREAT REVEREND CECIL WILLIAMS AND AND JANICE MIRIKITANI,
FORMER FORMER POET LAUREATE BUT ALSO IN THE NEW DAY OF OUR NEW
PRESIDENT AND CEO DR. GINA FROMER.
IT'S AN AMAZING THING TO BE ABLE TO WALK FROM CECIL
AND THEN WALK WITH DR. FROMER TOWARDS THIS NEW LEGACY IN THIS
NEW VISION OF GLIDE. >> I THINK MY PROUDEST MOMENT
IS YES, THIS AWARD BUT ALSO THAT PEOPLE LOOK AT ME AND GO
HIM YOU MEAN HE GETS TO YOU MEAN THAT SAME ONE THAT WAS
AND I'VE SEEN BLACK GAY MEN BECOME ACTIVISTS AND LEADERS.
I'VE SEEN SENIOR WOMEN BECOME LEADERS AND ADVOCATES.
I'VE SEEN PEOPLE BECOME ARTISTS ONLY BECAUSE THEY'VE
SEEN ME AND THEY KNOW THAT IT'S POSSIBLE THAT WE CAN START
WHEREVER WE ARE. SO I AM HONORED I AM HONORED TO
LIVE IN A CITY AND IN A PLACE WHERE WHAT YOUR LIFE
EXPERIENCES CAN DETERMINE WHAT YOU CAN GIVE TO THE CITY.
IT DOESN'T EXEMPT YOU OR EXCLUDE YOU FROM ANYTHING.
IT IS THE PLACE WHERE YOU START YOUR MINISTRY AND YOUR ACTIVISM
AND YOUR ARTISTRY. >> SO THANK YOU SO MUCH TO MY
FRIENDS AND FAMILIES AND COLLEAGUES AND MY COMMUNITY
AS WELL. I LOVE SERVING AND WORKING
ALONGSIDE YOU ALL. >> THANK YOU AGAIN SUPERVISOR
FOR THIS HONOR
. >> DISTRICT SIX SUPERVISOR
DORSEY THANK YOU PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN.
COLLEAGUES AS WE CELEBRATE LEADERS FROM OUR LGBTQ PLUS
COMMUNITY FOR PRIDE MONTH IT IS MY DISTINCT HONOR TO RECOGNIZE
JAMES JIM HOSS. >> JIM.
COME ON UP TO THE LECTERN. >> NOW JIM IS A LONG TIME
DISTRICT SIX RESIDENT WHOSE LEGACY ISN'T LIMITED TO THE
CAUSE OF LGBTQ PLUS EQUALITY THAT HE HAS CHAMPIONED FOR MORE
THAN 50 YEARS. IN FACT, HIS LEGACY INCLUDES A
CITY THAT IS MORE BEAUTIFUL, MORE WALKABLE, MORE LIVABLE
AND IN EVERY RESPECT TRUER TO ITS RICH HERITAGE AND STORIED
HISTORY THANKS IN LARGE PART TO HIS URBANIST VISION
AND ACTIVISM THAT WAS OFTEN YEARS AHEAD OF HIS TIME.
JIM HOSS IS A FIFTH GENERATION SAN FRANCISCAN WHOSE
CONTRIBUTIONS TO OUR CITY AND ITS LGBTQ PLUS COMMUNITY
SPANS DECADES. AFTER GRADUATING FROM STANFORD
IN 1964 AND COLUMBIA LAW SCHOOL IN 1969, JIM PRACTICED LAW
UNTIL HIS RETIREMENT IN 2010 SPECIALIZING IN REAL ESTATE
AND LAND USE. BEYOND HIS LEGAL CAREER,
HOWEVER, IT IS JIM'S LGBTQ PLUS ADVOCACY AND EXTRAORDINARY
PUBLIC SERVICE WE CELEBRATE TODAY.
>> IN 1983 JIM BEGAN HOSTING MEETINGS IN HIS KITCHEN.
SMALL GATHERINGS THAT WOULD SPARK HISTORIC PROGRESS TOWARD
LGBTQ PLUS INCLUSION. FROM THOSE MEETINGS CAME THE
BAY AREA NONPROFIT NONPARTISAN ALLIANCE SAN FRANCISCO'S FIRST
LGBTQ PLUS POLITICAL ACTION COMMITTEE.
IT WOULD RAISE AND DISTRIBUTE FUNDS TO SUPPORT MANY
CANDIDATES AND CAUSES AND IT WOULD EVENTUALLY BE FOLDED INTO
CALIFORNIA'S FIRST STATEWIDE LGBTQ PLUS PAC TO BROADEN ITS
MISSION. JIM HELPED LAY THE FOUNDATION
FOR GENERATIONS OF LGBTQ PLUS POLITICAL ENGAGEMENT
AND REPRESENTATION WORKING AMONG OTHERS WITH THE LATE JIM
RIVALDO WHOM I CONSIDER A FRIEND AND MENTOR.
IN 2004 DURING SAN FRANCISCO'S HISTORIC WINTER OF LOVE.
JIM SERVED AS A VOLUNTEER MARRIAGE COUNSELOR OFFICIATING
WEDDINGS FOR 30 COUPLES. IT WAS A MOMENT OF JOY
AND COURAGE IN OUR CITY'S LONG MARCH TOWARD EQUALITY AND JIM
HELPED MAKE IT REAL ONCE CEREMONY AT A TIME.
BUT JIM'S CIVIC IMPACT REACHES FAR BEYOND LGBTQ PLUS ISSUES
ALONE. AT HIS URGING, THEN SUPERVISOR
JACK MOLINARI WITH THE ENDORSEMENT OF THEN SUPERVISOR
HARVEY MILK WHO SAT AT THIS VERY DESK INTRODUCED THE BALLOT
MEASURE IN THE LATE 1970S TO CREATE OUR ELECTED CHARTER
COMMISSION. THAT MEASURE PASSED.
JIM WAS ELECTED A COMMISSIONER AND ALTHOUGH IT TOOK ANOTHER
DECADE AND A HALF THAT COMMISSION'S DRAFT EVENTUALLY
BECAME THE BASIS FOR SAN FRANCISCO'S MODERN CITY CHARTER
OF 1996. JIM WOULD GO ON TO CHAIR THE
CITIZEN'S TRANSPORTATION COMMITTEE IN THE 1980S HELPING
TO PASS TAX MEASURES THAT FUNDED KEY TRANSPORTATION
IMPROVEMENTS AND THAT WOULD CREATE THE SAN FRANCISCO COUNTY
TRANSPORTATION AGENCY. HE ALSO LED THE EMBARCADERO
FREEWAY CITIZEN'S COMMITTEE WHICH SUCCESSFULLY BATTLED A
MULTITUDE OF POWERFUL INTERESTS TO FINALLY TEAR DOWN THE
EMBARCADERO FREEWAY A CIVIC EYESORE THAT FOR 30 YEARS
BLOCKED ACCESS TO OUR CHERISHED WATERFRONT AND THAT WAS DAMAGED
IN THE 1989 LOMA PRIETA EARTHQUAKE.
NOW TODAY MOST PEOPLE HAVE EITHER FORGOTTEN OR MAYBE NEVER
KNEW HOW HERCULEAN A POLITICAL TASK IT WAS TO REMOVE THAT
FREEWAY. VOTERS HAD SOUNDLY REJECTED A
1986 BALLOT MEASURE BY A 2 TO 1 MARGIN TO TEAR IT DOWN.
AND THAT IT FINALLY HAPPENED IS TESTAMENT TO JIM'S LEADERSHIP
AND PERSISTENCE. JIM HAS ALSO BEEN A TIRELESS
ADVOCATE FOR OUR CIVIC CENTER FIGHTING FOR IMPROVEMENTS
THERE. FOR MORE THAN TWO DECADES FROM
SUPPORTING THE CAMPAIGN FOR A NEW MAIN LIBRARY TO HELPING
RESTORE CITY HALL TO ORGANIZING THE MAYOR'S FIRST CIVIC CENTER
STAKEHOLDERS MEETING IN 2019 JIM PUBLISHED THE SAN FRANCISCO
CIVIC CENTER, A DEEPLY RESEARCHED BOOK THAT CAPTURES
THE HISTORY AND MEANING OF ONE OF OUR CITY'S MOST ICONIC
SPACES. IT IS AVAILABLE ON AMAZON
AND KINDLE. THIS IS A REQUIRED READING FOR
ANYONE WHO WANTS TO UNDERSTAND THE HISTORIC HEART OF SAN
FRANCISCO AND TO GAIN INSIGHTS FROM THIS AS A BLUEPRINT TO
FULFILL THE PROMISE OF CIVIC CENTER FOR GENERATION TO COME
TODAY. JIM REMAINS A THOUGHTFUL
CONTRIBUTOR TO OUR CIVIC CONVERSATIONS AN INFLUENTIAL
URBANIST, A VALUED MEMBER OF THE DISTRICT SIX OFFICERS
UNOFFICIAL BRAIN TRUST AND WHETHER IT'S ADVOCATING FOR
CLEANER STREETS PUBLIC SAFETY OR SIMPLY OFFERING A WELL-TIMED
BIT OF WISDOM. JIM LEADS BY EXAMPLE DURING
PRIDE MONTH AS WE HONOR THOSE WE'VE WHO'VE PAVED THE WAY FOR
LGBT Q PLUS RIGHTS AND REPRESENTATION IT IS
ESPECIALLY FITTING THAT WE RECOGNIZE JIM HAS NOT JUST FOR
WHAT HE HAS DONE BUT FOR HOW HE HAS DONE IT WITH INTEGRITY,
WITH PURPOSE AND WITH A LIFELONG COMMITMENT TO THE CITY
HE LOVES AND CALLS HOME. JIM ON BEHALF OF A GRATEFUL
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS, A GRATEFUL LGBTQ PLUS COMMUNITY
AND A GRATEFUL CITY, WE THANK YOU FOR YOUR LIFETIME OF
SERVICE AND YOUR EFFECTIVE ADVOCACY ADVOCACY.
>> WE PROUDLY CELEBRATE YOU TODAY.
SUPERVISORS I'M HUMBLED BY SUPERVISOR DORIS IS CHOOSING ME
FOR THIS HONOR. YES, I'VE BEEN AROUND FOR A
LONG TIME AND I HAVE ROOTS TO GO EVEN FURTHER.
I THINK THAT MADE ME FEEL PARTICULARLY OBLIGED TO INVEST
MY SPARE TIME AND ENERGY INTO THE CITY.
>> I DON'T KNOW IF ANY OF YOU REMEMBER.
I THINK IT WAS THE KAISER CEMENT COMPANY HAD AN AD THAT
SAID FIND A NEED AND FILL IT. >> AND THAT'S SORT OF WHAT I
DID. I TOOK ON TASKS THAT NEEDED TO
BE DONE OFTEN AND NOBODY ELSE WAS PARTICULARLY INTERESTED
IN THEM. >> AND I GOT INVOLVED.
I HAVE TO SAY THE SUPERVISOR DORSEY THAT MANY OF THESE
PROJECTS I GOT INVOLVED WITH INVITED INVOLVED QUITE A BIT OF
A CONNIVING AND OTHER MISS OR PERHAPS UNDERHANDED TECHNIQUES
TO GET THEM DONE AND BUT THE GOAL WAS TO TO GET THEM GOING.
I GUESS I I'M PROUDEST OF TWO THINGS THE THE WORK FOR THE SAN
FRANCISCO COMMITTEE THE SALES TAX THAT WAS SORT OF A FREE
FLOATING COMMITTEE. MARY AGNES WASN'T PARTICULARLY
INTERESTED IN IT. THE SUPERVISORS HADN'T AT THAT
TIME HAD A LITTLE IDEA OF WHAT IT WAS ALL ABOUT.
AND THERE WAS A PERIOD OF TIME WHEN MARY AGNES WASN'T EVEN
TALKING TO ME. >> BUT WE GOT IT PASSED AND BY
55% THOSE WERE THE DAYS WHEN YOU COULD GET THINGS PASSED BY
55%. >> AND I I'VE NEVER ASKED BUT I
SUSPECT THAT THE SALES TAX AND THE RELATED ACTIVITIES OF
THE SAN FRANCISCO COUNTY TRANSPORTATION AUTHORITY HAS
GENERATED SEVERAL BILLIONS OF DOLLARS INVESTMENT
IN TRANSPORTATION IN THE CITY. >> AND OF COURSE YOU ALL THE
MEMBERS OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS WHO ARE THE
COMMISSIONERS GET TO GO TO MONTHLY MEETINGS AND YOU GET
YOUR $150 STIPEND AS WELL. >> AND THE OTHER THING IS MY
WORK AT CIVIC CENTER FIRST WITH THE LIBRARY AND YOU KNOW,
WRITING THAT BOOK WAS A GREAT ACHIEVEMENT FOR ME.
>> THERE WAS A RUMOR SPREAD BY A WORK COLLEAGUE OF MINE THAT I
COULDN'T WRITE ANYTHING. AND OF COURSE THE BOOK CAME
OUT. IT WAS PUBLISHED BY THE
UNIVERSITY OF NEVADA PRESS. AND I HAD THE GOOD FORTUNE OF
HAVING THE GREAT CALIFORNIA HISTORIAN KEVIN STARR GUIDING
ME AND URGING ME ON TO GET IT DONE.
>> BUT IT IS KIND OF THE TEMPLATE OF WHERE WE ARE
AND WHY THIS IS IMPORTANT. AND BECAUSE I FOUND THAT BEFORE
THAT PEOPLE HAD NO IDEA THAT THIS WAS ALL ABOUT AND WHY IT
CAME ABOUT AND WHAT ITS SIGNIFICANCE WAS.
AND I'M NOW 83 AND I'M NOT QUITE DONE YET.
THERE'S MORE THINGS TO DO TO COMPLETE AND IMPROVE CIVIC
CENTER AND I HOPE I HAVE SEVERAL MORE YEARS TO TO SEE
THAT. SO I THANK YOU FOR THIS HONOR
AND THE OPPORTUNITY TO REVEAL MY LIFE'S ACTIVITIES IN THE
PUBLIC REALM. BEFORE THE PUBLIC CAN
OKAY. OKAY.
THANKS. OKAY.
TIM, I CARRY THIS FOR YOU. >> DISTRICT NINE SUPERVISOR
FIELDER THANKS, PRESIDENT. >> GENTLEMEN, I'D LIKE TO
WELCOME UP TO THE PODIUM. MALIA SPANIEL AND THE WHOLE
CREW AT MOTHER BAR. >> PLEASE COME BACK.
I AM SO HONORED TO RECOGNIZE MOTHER BARD TODAY.
A LESBIAN AND BAR IN THE HEART OF THE MISSION ON 16TH STREET.
MOTHER IS MORE THAN JUST A BAR. IT'S A SANCTUARY WHERE ALL
IDENTITIES ARE EMBRACED AND CELEBRATED.
>> IT'S A PLACE WHERE WOMEN FIND COMMUNITY JOY
AND BELONGING. BORN FROM A VISION TO FILL A
LONGS STANDING GAP IN SAN FRANCISCO'S NIGHTLIFE MOTHER
BAR HAS BECOME A HOME BASE FOR WOMEN AND FEMMES THAT HAVE
LACKED A PLACE THAT CENTERED OUR EXPERIENCES.
>> AT THE HEART OF MOTHER IS MALIA ESPANOL.
MALIA HAS BEEN SHAPING SAN FRANCISCO CULTURAL SPACES FOR
YEARS FROM RUNNING BELOVED BARS LIKE PUBS AND THE PARK SIDE TO
OPENING UP HER OWN MUAY THAI GYM.
MALIA HAS CREATED SPACES WHERE CONNECTIONS FLOURISH WITH
MOTHER. >> SHE CREATED SOMETHING REALLY
SPECIAL. SHE CREATED A NEIGHBORHOOD BAR
WHERE PEOPLE FEEL SAFE, FEEL SEEN AND FEEL CELEBRATED.
>> MOTHER KEEPS WOMEN'S HISTORY ALIVE WHILST BUILDING
SOMETHING NEW. >> IT STANDS AS A REMINDER THAT
JOY IS VITAL ESPECIALLY RIGHT NOW AND SPACES LIKE THESE ARE
NECESSARY TO OUR SURVIVAL. A MOTHER IS HELPING SHAPE THE
FUTURE OF SAN FRANCISCO WITH EVERY NIGHT IT OPENS ITS DOORS.
IT'S MORE THAN JUST A PLACE TO PARTY.
IT'S A SANCTUARY, A CELEBRATION IN AND A REMINDER OF THE POWER
OF CHOSEN FAMILY. >> TO MALIA AND ALL THE FOLKS
HERE THE ENTIRE MOTHER TEAM. >> I EXTEND MY DEEPEST
GRATITUDE ESPECIALLY AS A WOMAN OF COLOR.
>> THANK YOU FOR CREATING A SPACE THAT FEELS LIKE HOME
WHERE JOY, SELF-EXPRESSION AND COMMUNITY FLOURISH.
YOUR UNWAVERING COMMITMENT TO THE LGBTQ COMMUNITY DOESN'T
JUST INSPIRE. IT UPLIFTS AND EMPOWERS US ALL.
>> AND CONGRATULATIONS ON ALL YOU'VE BUILT AND HAPPY PRIDE.
HERE'S TO SO MANY MORE NIGHTS OF MAGIC MUSIC AND LOVE.
>> HI. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR ALL YOU DO. >> I'M A LITTLE UNPREPARED.
I CAME TO THE CITY 35 YEARS AGO.
>> I SPENT 25 IN THE MISSION DISTRICT.
>> BUT IN THE 90S SORT OF THE COMMUNITY WAS THRIVING.
AND WE HAD SPACES AND EVENTS AND ARTISTS AND YOU KNOW WE HAD
WE HAD SUCH A COMMUNITY. AND I'VE SLOWLY SEEN THAT SORT
OF DISAPPEAR AND COMING OUT OF COVID I LOOKED AROUND FOR
COMMUNITY AND COULD NOT FIND IT.
AND SO IN SORT OF A A LOVE LETTER OR AN OFFERING TO THE
COMMUNITY AND TO THE YOUTH OF THE CITY, I THOUGHT IT WAS
IMPORTANT TO OPEN THE BAR AND I FOUND THESE GUYS.
AND YOU KNOW, I CREATE THE BONES AND THEY REALLY ARE THE
LIKE THE HEARTBEAT OF OF THE BAR.
AND THANK YOU SO MUCH AND THANK YOU TO ALL OF YOU GUYS
AND LET'S JUST KEEP ON PROVIDING THE SPACE FOR YOU
KNOW, EVERYONE IN THE CITY. >> DISTRICT ONE SUPERVISOR CHAN
THANK YOU PRESIDENT MENDELSOHN COLLEAGUES IT IS TRULY A
PRIVILEGE TO BE ABLE TO INVITE AND RECOGNIZE MALENA LIM A
CELEBRATING A CELEBRATED FILMMAKER, PRODUCER, DIRECTOR,
ADJUNCT PROFESSOR AND LONG TIME LGBTQ ACTIVIST WHOSE FILMS HAVE
BEEN SCREENED AT SOLD OUT THEATERS AT FILM FESTIVAL FROM
ACROSS THE WORLD. HER WORK HAS BEEN EMBELLISHED
WITH NUMEROUS PROCEDURES AND HIGHLY COMPETITIVE AWARDS
THAT IS TOO MANY TO NAME. HER WORK HAS ALSO BEEN FEATURED
AT PROMINENT LOCAL INSTITUTIONS INCLUDING DE YOUNG AND ASIAN
ART MUSEUM AND BROADCASTED TO MILLIONS OF AUDIENCE ON PBS.
MADELINE'S ACTIVISM STARTED IN HER EARLY 20S.
SHE RAN AN UNDERGROUND LESBIAN FEMINIST NEWSLETTER
IN SINGAPORE FOR TWO YEARS AND LATER BECAME ACTIVELY
INVOLVED IN THE ASSOCIATION OF WOMEN FOR ACTION AND RESEARCH,
AN ORGANIZATION THAT ADVOCATES FOR GENDER EQUALITY
AND PROVIDES CRITICAL SUPPORT SERVICES FOR WOMEN
IN SINGAPORE. IN 1987 MADELINE CO-WROTE
AND DIRECTED A SKIT CALLED THE MYTH PAGEANT BEAUTY CONTEST A
PARODY ON THE MISS PAGEANT BEAUTY CONTEST IN CELEBRATION
OF INTERNATIONAL WOMEN'S DAY. SHORTLY AFTER THE EVENT, HER
COAUTHOR WAS ARRESTED BY THE SINGAPORE GOVERNMENT.
MADELINE ESCAPED PERSECUTION AND EVENTUALLY MADE HER WAY TO
SAN FRANCISCO. TEN YEARS LATER SHE CREATED THE
AWARD WINNING DOCUMENT FREE SAMBA BALAKIAN IN SAN FRANCISCO
IN 1997 A FILM THAT IS STILL BANNED IN SINGAPORE FOR ITS
EXPLORATION OF RACE, SEXUALITY AND NATIONALITY CONTINUING TO
SEE A LACK OF PROPER REPRESENTATION FOR WOMEN OF
COLOR EVEN IN SAN FRANCISCO. SHE CO-FOUNDED CAREER WOMEN OF
COLOR MEDIA ARTS PROJECT CRACK MAP, A LOCAL ORGANIZATION THAT
SUPPORTS THE CREATION AND DISTRIBUTION OF FILMS THAT
ADDRESS CURRENT SOCIAL ISSUE AFFECTING LGBTQ PLUS WOMEN OF
COLOR AND THEIR COMMUNITIES. WOMEN OF COLOR MEDIA ARTS
PROJECT THAT PROVIDES TRAINING, SCREENING OPPORTUNITIES
AND RESOURCE TO FILMMAKERS SO THEY CAN AUTHENTICALLY REFLECT
THEIR LIFE STORIES AND BUILD COMMUNITY THROUGH ART
AND ACTIVISM PARTICULARLY DURING THIS TIME WHEN SO MANY
OF OUR IMMIGRANT AND OUR OUTPUT PLUS COMMUNITY MEMBERS ARE
UNDER ATTACK BY OUR OWN FEDERAL GOVERNMENT.
I KNOW THAT SAN FRANCISCO MUST CONTINUE TO AMPLIFY AND MAKE
SPACE FOR CAREER WOMEN OF COLOR TO TELL THEIR STORIES.
AND I AM JUST SO PROUD AND AND THAT WE GET A CHANCE TO INVITE
HER TO BE HERE BUT TO ALSO SAY THAT I THINK OFTENTIMES A WOMAN
OF COLOR IS DEFINITELY IN ASIA OR REALLY CONTINUE TO BE NOT
ONLY MARGINALIZED BUT ALSO CRIMINALIZED ON SO MANY LEVEL
THROUGH SO MANY LAYERS AND THEIR STORIES ARE NOT TOLD
AND OFTENTIMES THEY'RE LEFT BEHIND.
BUT TO HAVE SOMEONE LIKE MADELINE LIM AND WILLING TO
TELL THEIR STORIES AND UNDERSTAND THE RISK TO TAKE
THAT THEY MUST TAKE AND THE FILMMAKERS THEMSELVES AS WELL
AND JUST TO BE ABLE TO CREATE A SAFE SPACE FOR THEM TO TELL
THAT STORIES IS JUST AMAZING. AND FOR THAT I'M JUST SO
GRATEFUL NOT JUST FOR THE WOMEN OF COLOR RIGHT NOW BUT
REALLY FOR THE GENERATIONS TO COME SO THAT THEY HOPEFULLY ONE
DAY MAYBE TAKE THIS FOR GRANTED TO BE ABLE TO SAY YES, THIS IS
A SAFE SPACE AND THIS IS THEIR ROLE AND THAT THEY CAN BE
PROUDLY TO BE WHO THEY ARE NOT JUST IN UNITED STATES OR SAN
FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA BUT ALL AROUND THE GLOBE.
>> AND SO THANK YOU FOR YOUR CONTRIBUTION.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON, EVERYONE. THANK YOU SO MUCH TO ALL OF THE
SUPERVISORS. PRESIDENT MENDEL MIN
AND ESPECIALLY CONNIE CHEN FOR THIS RECOGNITION.
I AM DEEPLY HUMBLED AND TOUCHED IN THE 70S I WAS A TEEN COMING
OF AGE AND I WAS PULLED OUT OF MY CLASSES BY THE SCHOOL
PRINCIPAL BEING COUNSELED TO BE STRAIGHT, GET A BOYFRIEND, PUT
ON MAKEUP. I ALMOST DID NOT SURVIVE MY
COMING OUT. >> AND AS SUPERVISOR CONNIE
CHEN MENTIONED I ESCAPED SINGAPORE BECAUSE I WAS DOING
UNDERGROUND LGBTQ ORGANIZING AND IT WAS GETTING DANGEROUS.
I WAS IN MY EARLY 20S AND I DID NOT YOU KNOW WHO WANTS TO WHO
ENVISIONS HANGING OUT IN JAIL, RIGHT?
I DID NOT. AND I CAME TO SAN FRANCISCO.
IT WAS MY SANCTUARY. SAN FRANCISCO IS A BEACON FOR
SO MANY FOR THOSE OF US WHO ARE LGBTQ.
THOSE OF US WHO ARE IMMIGRANTS AND ARTISTS IT'S FILMMAKING
KICKED MY BUT IT WAS MY CALLING.
I THINK I KNEW I WAS A FILMMAKER WHEN I WAS DEEPLY
ENGAGED IN AN ARGUMENT. >> I WAS 15.
MY GIRLFRIEND WAS A YEAR YOUNGER AND YOU KNOW THOSE
ARGUMENTS AT THAT AGE ARE LIFE AND DEATH LITERALLY.
>> AND I REMEMBER STOPPING THE ARGUMENT FOR A SECOND THINKING
IN MY HEAD THIS MIGHT MAKE AN INTERESTING FILM ONE DAY
AND THEN I WENT BACK TO MY ARGUMENT.
>> I MADE A DOCUMENTARY CALLED SOME MARBLE ARCH AND IN SAN
FRANCISCO THROUGH SAN FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITIES PROGRAM IT
WON SEVERAL AWARDS. IT TAUGHT INTERNATIONAL FILM
FESTIVAL FOR ABOUT 2 OR 3 YEARS AT EVERY FILM FESTIVAL THAT I
ATTENDED WHETHER IT WAS LGBTQ FILM FESTIVAL OR PEOPLE OF
COLOR FILM FESTIVAL OR HUMAN RIGHTS FILM FESTIVAL.
I FOUND MYSELF AMONG ONE HANDFUL OF WOMEN OF COLOR
FILMMAKERS AND IT OCCURRED TO ME IF WE ARE NOT THE ONES
TELLING OUR OWN STORIES, OUR OWN LIVES, OUR OWN COMMUNITIES
,OUR OWN EXPERIENCES WHO WILL I KNEW AS AN INDEPENDENT
FILMMAKER I WOULD MAKE ONE FILM EVERY 3 TO 5 YEARS BECAUSE OF
THE FUNDRAISING INVOLVED. BUT I KNEW IF I TAUGHT
FILMMAKING I COULD TEACH AN ART FORM THAT IS SO EXPENSIVE THAT
HAS AN ECONOMIC BARRIER ASSOCIATED WITH IT.
IN ONE YEAR IF I HAVE 40 PARTICIPANTS IN TEN YEARS I
WOULD HAVE HAD 400 PARTICIPANTS IN 25 YEARS WE HAVE HAD OVER
500 FILMS CREATED BY OUR WOMEN OF COLOR BY NON-BINARY
TRANSGENDER PEOPLE OF COLOR COMMUNITIES 500 PLUS FILMS.
NO OTHER ARTS INSTITUTION IN THE WORLD HAS THIS
COLLECTION OF FILMS ABOUT OUR COMMUNITY.
I WAS SO NOT TRYING TO START A NONPROFIT.
I WAS REALLY TRYING TO MAKE CHANGE AND IT HAPPENED TO BE
THROUGH FILM AND TEACHING. WE JUST PRESENTED OUR ANNUAL
FILM FESTIVAL WAS OUR 21ST WOMEN OF COLOR FILM FESTIVAL A
COUPLE OF WEEKS AGO AT THE PRESIDIO THEATER.
WE HAD OVER 1500 PEOPLE COME THROUGH THE THREE DAYS WE
SCREENED OVER 49 FILMS THROUGH SEVEN SCREENING PROGRAMS.
>> IT TOOK US 20 YEARS TO GROW OUR ORGANIZATION BUDGET TO
$500,000. 20 YEARS BECAUSE RACISM,
SEXISM, HOMOPHOBIA ARE BLATANT IN FUNDRAISING.
>> WOMEN OF COLOR ARE CONSTANTLY PERCEIVED AS A NICHE
WITHIN A NICHE WITHIN A NICHE WHEN IN FACT WE ARE REALLY
BRIDGES WHEN THAT HAPPENS OUR LIVES ARE DEVALUED, OUR WORK
DISMISSED. >> THIS YEAR MARKS OUR 25TH
ANNIVERSARY OF OUR ORGANIZATION.
IT'S A HUGE MILESTONE FOR US. HOWEVER, IN MARCH UNFORTUNATELY
WE HAD A GRANT TWO GRANTS ACTUALLY FROM THE SAN FRANCISCO
HUMAN RIGHTS COMMISSION CANCELED AND $500,000 IS HALF
OF OUR ORGANIZATIONAL BUDGET. >> IT WAS NOT FAIR.
IT WAS WRONG. IT WAS UNJUST AND UNFORTUNATELY
THERE IS NO RECOURSE. >> IT WOULD HAVE SUPPORTED A
SECOND YEAR OF OUR CAREER AND TRANS BLACK FILMMAKERS
ARTISTS FELLOWSHIP PROGRAM. NO SIMILAR PROGRAM EXISTS
IN THE ENTIRE COUNTRY EXCEPT HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
>> KWOK MAPP. THE SECOND GRANT WOULD HAVE
SUPPORTED A AND TRANS APPRENTICESHIP PROGRAM.
IT WOULD BOTH GRANTS WOULD HAVE DEVELOPED, WORKFORCE WOULD HAVE
BEEN WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT. THERE WERE 38 ORGANIZATIONS
THAT GOT THEIR GRANTS CANCELED. >> THEY WERE ALL PEOPLE OF
COLOR LED ORGANIZATIONS THAT SERVED PEOPLE OF COLOR
COMMUNITIES. >> SO SAN FRANCISCO IS A BEACON
SHINING BRIGHTLY GLOBALLY. THIS BEACON IS MADE UP OF
HUNDREDS OF DIVERSE MULTIPLE LIGHTS LIGHTS THAT ARE OUR
GRASSROOTS COMMUNITY BASED NONPROFIT ORGANIZATIONS THAT
PROVIDE A MUCH NEEDED ANCHOR ESPECIALLY RIGHT NOW DURING
THIS TUMULTUOUS, UNPREDICTABLE STORMY PERIOD.
HUNDREDS OF LOCAL LIGHTS COMING TOGETHER TO CREATE THIS GLOBAL
BEACON THAT WE LIVE AND CALL HOME IN SAN FRANCISCO.
I IMPLORE YOU SUPPORT YOUR LOCAL ANCHOR ARTS AND CULTURE
ORGANIZATION QUAKE MAP IS LED IMMIGRANT LED PEOPLE OF COLOR
LED. PROTECT THE MOST VULNERABLE
AMONG US BECAUSE IF WE DON'T WHO WILL?
>> WE ARE CELEBRATING PRIDE. >> TO BE HONEST MY HEART IS
HEAVY. THIS BUDGET CUTS HAVE HAD AN
EMOTIONAL PHYSICAL MENTAL IMPACT TOLL ON ALL OF US.
WE HAVE BEEN OPERATING ON RESERVES ALL YEAR.
IT'S OUR 25TH ANNIVERSARY AND I AM AFRAID THAT OUR DOORS MIGHT
NOT STAY OPEN AFTER THIS YEAR. >> SO THANK YOU FOR THIS
RECOGNITION. >> IT IS MUCH APPRECIATED
AND HAPPY PRIDE TO EVERYONE. ALL RIGHT COLLEAGUES.
THAT BRINGS US TO DISTRICT EIGHT AND I AM GOING TO BEG
YOUR FORGIVE THIS. LAST YEAR I OF COURSE FOR JUNE
WE GET VERY EXCITED ABOUT LINING UP SPECIAL LGBTQ
INDIVIDUALS TO GET HONORED AT EACH OF OUR TUESDAY BOARD
MEETINGS AND LAST WEEK BECAUSE OF CIRCUMSTANCES BEYOND OUR
CONTROL, OUR HONOREE WAS NOT ABLE TO BE HONORED AND SO I
INVITED HER TO COME BACK. BUT WE ALSO HAVE ANOTHER GREAT
HONOREE FOR TODAY SO WE'RE GOOD.
I'M GIVING MYSELF A PRESIDENTIAL PRIVILEGE
PRIVILEGE TO DO 2 IN 1 DAY AND I BEG YOUR FORGIVENESS.
FIRST UP I'M GOING TO ASK RON GALLMAN TO COME UP.
>> SO RON IS THE SAN FRANCISCO SYMPHONY'S LONGTIME DIRECTOR OF
EDUCATION AND YOUTH ORCHESTRA AND HE IS RETIRING THIS MONTH
AFTER 42 YEARS OF SERVICE TO THE SYMPHONY.
>> SINCE JOINING THE SYMPHONY STAFF IN 1983, RON HAS BEEN A
VISIONARY LEADER WHOSE WORK HAS TRANSFORMED THE WAY ORCHESTRAS
ENGAGE WITH THEIR COMMUNITIES. APPOINTED DIRECTOR OF EDUCATION
AND YOUTH ORCHESTRA IN 1995, RON HAS OVERSEEN THE
CONCEPTUALIZATION, IMPLEMENTATION AND MANAGEMENT
OF THE SYMPHONY'S PORTFOLIO OF EDUCATIONAL PROGRAMS
INITIATIVES THAT HAVE BECOME NATIONAL MODELS UNDER HIS
LEADERSHIP. DESCRIBED BY THE WALL STREET
JOURNAL AS THE INDUSTRY STANDARD AND HAILED BY THE NEW
YORK TIMES AS A MUSIC EDUCATION POWERHOUSE.
THESE PROGRAMS HAVE OPENED THE DOOR, OPENED THE WORLD OF MUSIC
TO COUNTLESS YOUNG PEOPLE AND FAMILIES THROUGHOUT HIS
TENURE RON HAS LED WITH HEART HUMILITY AND THE STRONG
CONVICTION THAT MUSIC HAS THE POWER TO INSPIRE AND MOTIVATE
YOUNG MUSICIANS. >> HE LAUNCHED AND CONTINUOUSLY
GREW THE ADVENTURES IN MUSIC PROGRAM WHICH HAS REACHED EVERY
STUDENT IN GRADES ONE THROUGH FIVE AND SAN FRANCISCO'S PUBLIC
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS SINCE 1988. HE'S OVERSEEN CONCERTS FOR KIDS
MUSIC FOR FAMILIES INSIDE MUSIC AND SFX KIDS.ORG THE SYMPHONY'S
INTERACTIVE DIGITAL LEARNING PLATFORM.
>> HIS COMMITMENT TO YOUNG MUSICIANS IS PERHAPS BEST
REFLECTED IN HIS STEWARDSHIP OF THE SAN FRANCISCO SYMPHONY
YOUTH ORCHESTRA, WHICH HAS FLOURISHED UNDER HIS GUIDANCE
AS ONE OF THE FINEST ENSEMBLES OF ITS KIND IN THE WORLD.
RON ALSO CHAMPIONED LIFELONG LEARNING AND COMMUNITY
ENGAGEMENT THROUGH PROGRAMS LIKE COMMUNITY OF MUSIC MAKERS
WHICH BROUGHT AMATEUR MUSICIANS ONTO THE STAGE AT DAVIS
SYMPHONY HALL TO MAKE MUSIC ALONGSIDE SYMPHONY
PROFESSIONALS ACROSS EVERY INITIATIVE.
RON HAS ENSURED THAT THE SYMPHONY'S EDUCATIONAL
OFFERINGS REFLECT THE HIGHEST STANDARDS OF EXCELLENCE, ACCESS
AND INCLUSION. IN ADDITION TO HIS WORK AT THE
SYMPHONY, RON HAS BEEN A POWERFUL ADVOCATE FOR ARTS
EDUCATION AT THE LOCAL, STATE AND NATIONAL LEVELS.
HE'S REPRESENTED SAN FRANCISCO AT CONFERENCES HOSTED BY THE
LEAGUE OF AMERICAN ORCHESTRAS, AMERICANS FOR THE ARTS AND THE
ARTS EDUCATION PARTNERSHIP AND HAS SERVED ON PANELS FOR
THE NATIONAL ENDOWMENT FOR THE ARTS AND THE CALIFORNIA ARTS
COUNCIL. HE'S A LONGTIME MEMBER OF THE
SAN FRANCISCO COMMUNITY MUSIC CENTER WHERE HE CHAIRED THE
PROGRAM COMMITTEE AND SERVED TWO TERMS AS CHAIR OF THE
NATIONAL EDUCATION LEADERSHIP COMMITTEE OF THE OF THE LEAGUE
OF AMERICAN ORCHESTRAS. A PROUD DISTRICT RESIDENT SINCE
1982, RON HAS ALSO CONTRIBUTED AS A PERFORMING ARTIST SINGING
FOR 40 YEARS AS A VOLUNTEER MEMBER OF THE SAN FRANCISCO
SYMPHONY CHORUS. HIS DEEP LOVE FOR MUSIC,
COMMUNITY AND PUBLIC SERVICE HAS LEFT AN ENDURING LEGACY
IN SAN FRANCISCO AND WELL BEYOND.
THANK YOU RON, FOR THE IMMEASURABLE IMPACT YOU'VE HAD
ON THE LIVES OF GENERATIONS OF STUDENTS, FAMILIES
AND MUSICIANS AND FOR YOUR CONTRIBUTIONS TO ENSURE THAT
SAN FRANCISCO REMAINS A GLOBAL LEADER IN ARTS AND CULTURE.
>> CONGRATULATIONS RON AND HAPPY RETIREMENT.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU SO MUCH.
PRESIDENT MANDOLIN AND THANK YOU TO THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. OF COURSE, AS YOU CAN IMAGINE,
I'M DEEPLY, DEEPLY HONORED TO RECEIVE THIS COMMENDATION.
IT'S WONDERFUL TO BE RECOGNIZED FOR 42 YEARS OF REALLY
DEDICATION AND SERVICE TO THE CAUSE OF THE ARTS AND ARTS
EDUCATION IN SAN FRANCISCO. >> MY WORK HAS BEEN WORKING
WITH THE ARTS ENSURING THAT EVERYONE HAS A PLACE IN THE
ARTS AND THAT THE ARTS CAN SERVE EVERYONE IN OUR CITY
AND ESPECIALLY SAN FRANCISCO'S PUBLIC SCHOOL CHILDREN.
BUT ALSO REACHING EVERY COMMUNITY OF SAN FRANCISCO OUR
STATE NATIONALLY AND BEYOND INTERNATIONALLY I MUST THANK
AND GIVE CREDIT TO THE SAN FRANCISCO SYMPHONY FOR ITS
ONGOING INVESTMENT IN MUSIC EDUCATION IN THIS CITY THAT
REALLY HAS FUELED MY WORK OVER THESE PAST FOUR DECADES.
BEING ASSOCIATED WITH AN ORGANIZATION THAT IS SO
COMMITTED TO ENSURING THAT AS A CORE PART OF ITS MISSION THAT
IT SERVES ITS COMMUNITY THROUGH ART AND ARTS EDUCATION SERVICES
AND OF COURSE I AM VERY, VERY PLEASED AND VERY MUCH INSPIRED
BY THE LONG STANDING RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN THE
SYMPHONY AND THE SAN FRANCISCO UNIFIED SCHOOL DISTRICT.
MY WORK WITH THE SAN FRANCISCO UNIFIED SCHOOL DISTRICT IS ALSO
ANOTHER ONE OF THOSE ASPECTS THAT HAS FUELED ME WORKING
IN PARTNERSHIP WITH THE DISTRICT TO ENSURE THAT EVERY
SINGLE CHILD IN SAN FRANCISCO GETS A WELL-ROUNDED
AND BALANCED EDUCATION THAT INCLUDES MUSIC AND THE ARTS.
>> I WOULD SAY THAT WE ALL KNOW THAT SUPPORT FOR THE ARTS IS
CRITICAL IN KEEPING SAN FRANCISCO THIS CITY VIBRANT.
>> AND AS I STEP DOWN FROM MY ROLE AS THE SAN FRANCISCO
SYMPHONY'S DIRECTOR OF EDUCATION AND YOUTH ORCHESTRA
AFTER 42 YEARS I VERY MUCH AM LOOKING FORWARD TO SEEING
WATCHING AND DOING WHAT I CAN TO HELP CONTINUE TO ENSURE THAT
THE ARTS REALLY REMAIN VIBRANT ,THAT THEY GROW AND THAT THEY
THRIVE BECAUSE THOSE CAN ONLY BE GOOD THINGS FOR US.
THE CITY OF SAN FRANCISCO. >> SO THANK YOU VERY, VERY MUCH
. >> I'M VERY, VERY HONORED
. >> >> ALL RIGHT.
>> ONE WEEK LATE. REBECCA RALPH, COME ON UP.
>> REBECCA HAS SPENT A LOT OF TIME IN THIS CHAMBER OVER THE
YEARS IN JUNE. IT HAS NOT ALWAYS BEEN
ENJOYABLE AND YOU'VE GOT TO SIT THROUGH TO SPECIAL
ACCOMMODATIONS. >> SO THANK YOU FOR STICKING
WITH IT FOR THIS FINAL TUESDAY OF PRIDE MONTH.
>> IT IS MY HONOR TO PRESENT A SPECIAL COMMENDATION TO REBECCA
RALPH WHO WILL BE RETIRING LATER THIS YEAR FROM THE SAN
FRANCISCO LGBT CENTER WHICH SHE HAS LED SO VERY CAPABLY FOR 17
YEARS. >> SHE JOINED THE CENTER STAFF
IN 2003 AS THE DEPUTY EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR ONE YEAR AFTER IT
FIRST OPENED ITS DOORS AT 1800 MARKET STREET.
IN THAT ROLE SHE OVERSAW THE ORGANIZATION'S BUDGET STAFF
AND COMMUNITY PROGRAMS. >> IN APRIL OF 2007 THE BOARD
SELECTED HER TO SERVE AS EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR.
SHE WOULD TURN OUT TO HAVE BEEN AN INSPIRED CHOICE DURING HER
NEARLY TWO DECADES LEADING THE CENTER.
SHE HAS HELPED TO MAKE IT ONE OF SAN FRANCISCO'S INDICES
SENSIBLE ORGANIZATIONS A COMMUNITY HUB THAT OFFERS
HOUSING RESOURCES, EMPLOYMENT AND FINANCIAL SERVICES, ARTS
AND CULTURE PROGRAMING AND SUPPORT FOR YOUTH AND TRANS
COMMUNITIES. THE MISSION OF THE LGBT CENTER
IS TO CONNECT OUR DIVERSE COMMUNITY TO OPPORTUNITIES,
RESOURCES AND EACH OTHER TO ACHIEVE OUR VISION OF A
STRONGER, HEALTHIER AND MORE EQUITABLE WORLD FOR LGBT PEOPLE
AND OUR ALLIES. >> THE MISSION IS AN INSPIRING
ONE BUT I DO NOT BELIEVE THE CENTER WOULD HAVE SURVIVED TO
FULFILL THAT MISSION WITHOUT REBECCA'S LEADERSHIP.
>> INDEED, IN ITS EARLY DAYS BURDENED BY CRUSHING
CONSTRUCTION, DEBT AND FINANCES THAT AS A CONSEQUENCE NEVER
QUITE BALANCED OUT THE CENTER'S SURVIVAL WAS AN OPEN QUESTION.
IN 2017 REBECCA AND HER BOARD PUT THAT QUESTION TO REST WITH
A $10.3 MILLION NEUMARK NEW MARKET TAX CREDIT FUNDED MAJOR
CAPITAL REMODEL THAT REMADE THE PHYSICAL STRUCTURE TO BETTER
SERVE COMMUNITY NEEDS AND GENERATE MORE REVENUE FOR
THE CENTER'S ONGOING OPERATIONS .
>> BEFORE SHE JOINED THE CENTER, REBECCA SERVED EIGHT
YEARS AS THE EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR FOR SAN FRANCISCO WOMEN AGAINST
RAPE MANAGING ITS BUDGET, DEVELOPING AND EXPANDING ITS
PROGRAMS AND RAISING GRANT FUNDS TO SUSTAIN A COMMUNITY
BASED RAPE RAPE CRISIS CENTER AND BETWEEN HER EXECUTIVE
DIRECTOR ROLES, REBECCA WORKED AS A POLICY ANALYST FOR OUR OWN
DEPARTMENT ON THE STATUS OF WOMEN.
HER WORK INVOLVED ANALYZING DATA RELATED TO GENDER
DISCRIMINATION ISSUES AFFECTING WOMEN AND MAKING
RECOMMENDATIONS FOR NEW POLICY .
>> REBECCA YOU HAVE ACCOMPLISHED AMAZING THINGS
IN YOUR PROFESSIONAL LIFE AND ESPECIALLY AT THE CENTER OF
THESE LAST 22 YEARS. IT HAS BEEN A PRIVILEGE TO BE
ABLE TO WORK WITH YOU, TO LEARN FROM YOU, TO BENEFIT FROM YOUR
COUNSEL. YOU RETIREMENT IS VERY
WELL-DESERVED BUT NONETHELESS BITTERSWEET FOR ME.
>> I DON'T WANT TO SAY I WILL MISS YOU BECAUSE I VERY MUCH
HOPE AND STRONGLY SUSPECT THAT YOU WILL CONTINUE TO FIND WAYS
TO ENGAGE IN THE FIGHTS FOR JUSTICE AND EQUALITY AND A MORE
PERFECT SAN FRANCISCO. FOR NOW I WILL JUST SAY REBECCA
RALPH, WE LOVE YOU VERY, VERY MUCH.
WE THANK YOU VERY, VERY MUCH. AND WITH THAT THE FLOOR IS
YOURS. >> THANK YOU SO MUCH, PRESIDENT
MANDELL MEN AND THANK YOU SO MUCH TO THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. I HAVE SPENT A LOT OF TIME
IN THIS CHAMBER AS RECENTLY AS YESTERDAY WHEN I HAD ONE MINUTE
LIMIT AND I WAS LIKE I'LL BE BACK TOMORROW.
>> NOW I KNOW YOUR HOSTAGE BUT I REALLY WANT TO ACCEPT THIS
AWARD ON BEHALF OF A COMMUNITY THAT THE COMMUNITY HERE IN SAN
FRANCISCO, THE INCREDIBLE BEAUTIFULLY BROADLY DIVERSE
COMMUNITY THAT WE ARE PART OF AND SERVE.
I WANT TO THANK THE PEOPLE THE CENTER'S BEEN A LABOR OF LOVE
NOT JUST FOR ME BUT FOR SO MANY PEOPLE WHO HAVE LABORED SO HARD
TO MAKE SURE THAT THIS IS AN INSTITUTION THAT LASTS FOR OUR
COMMUNITY AND THAT WHAT WE OFFER EVERY SINGLE DAY REALLY
SPEAKS TO THE BROAD NEEDS OF OUR COMMUNITY AND THAT WE
CONTINUE TO BE HERE TO TO MEET THOSE NEEDS TO FILL IN THE GAPS
TO IDENTIFY WHAT'S EMERGING BECAUSE THE TRUTH IS THAT
ACROSS THE COUNTRY OUR COMMUNITY IS UNDER ATTACK
AND THAT INCLUDES HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO ESPECIALLY TRANS
AND NON-BINARY INDIVIDUALS ALONG WITH IMMIGRANTS
AND ASYLUM SEEKERS, BLACK FOLKS WE ARE ALL UNDER ATTACK.
>> THE HATRED THAT WE ARE WITNESSING IS NOT NEW BUT IT IS
ESCALATING FROM POLICIES THAT SEEK TO ERASE OUR VERY
EXISTENCE TO WIDESPREAD FUNDING CUTS TO VITAL SAFETY NET
PROGRAMS TO THE TARGETING OF THOSE WHO DARE TO SPEAK OUT
AGAINST DISCRIMINATION AND RISING FASCISM.
THE THREATS ARE IMMINENT. EVEN IN SAN FRANCISCO WE
CONTINUE TO FACE THE IMPACT OF HOMOPHOBIA TRANSPHOBIA AND THE
IMPACT THE INTERSECTIONS OF RACISM AND GENDER BIAS
IN HOUSING, HEALTH CARE, EMPLOYMENT AND SAFETY.
AT THE SAME TIME WE'RE SEEING MORE PEOPLE ARRIVE SEEKING
SANCTUARY RESOURCES AND REFUGE. WE OWE IT TO EACH OTHER TO BE
READY TO MEET THAT NEED. >> AND ALL THIS IS HAPPENING AT
A TIME WHEN WE ARE FACING HUGE BUDGET CHALLENGES FROM THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT AND AT A LOCAL LEVEL AND THESE ARE
IMPACTING OUR PROGRAMS AND SERVICES AND AND RESULTING
IN REDUCED SERVICES FOR OUR COMMUNITY.
MOST TRAGICALLY FOR THE MOST VULNERABLE AND VULNERABLE
MEMBERS OF OUR COMMUNITY. >> LEADERSHIP MATTERS.
I REALLY APPRECIATE YOUR RECOGNIZING MY LEADERSHIP BUT
NO ONE LEADER CAN SOLVE WHAT WE'RE UP AGAINST.
>> IT IS GOING TO TAKE ALL OF US.
I LOOK FORWARD TO CONTINUING TO WORK WITH PARTNERSHIP
IN PARTNERSHIP WITH ALL OF YOU WITH THE INCREDIBLE
ORGANIZATIONS THAT MAKE UP THE FABRIC OF THIS COMMUNITY
IN THIS CITY WITH THE MANY CITIZENS THE COMMUNITY, ALL OF
OUR ALLIED COMMUNITIES BECAUSE TO FIND A SOLUTION WE NEED EACH
OTHER. WE NEED TO PROTECT EACH OTHER.
WE NEED TO SHOW UP FOR COMMUNITY.
WE NEED TO SHOW UP FOR EACH OTHER AND WE NEED TO INVEST
IN THE ORGANIZATIONS THAT WE WANT TO SEE UNDER THIS MOMENT.
SO THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THIS ON BEHALF OF COMMUNITY IT IS MY
PLEASURE AND MY HONOR TO SERVE SUCH AN INCREDIBLE COMMUNITY
AND TO STAND WITH SO MANY AMAZING LEADERS WHO ARE HONORED
HERE TODAY. I'M A LITTLE INTIMIDATED BUT
IT'S IT'S JUST A PLEASURE AND AN HONOR.
SO THANK YOU SO MUCH
. >> AND I THINK MADAM CLERK,
THAT TAKES US TO PUBLIC COMMENT.
>> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. AT THIS TIME THE BOARD WELCOMES
YOUR GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT. IF YOU'LL LINE UP ON THE RIGHT
HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER WE ARE SETTING THE TIMER FOR TWO
MINUTES. YOU MAY SPEAK TO THE APPROVAL
OF THE MAY 20TH BOARD MEETING MINUTES AS PRESENTED ITEMS 27
THROUGH 31 THE ITEM AND ITEMS ON THE ADOPTION BUT WITHOUT
REFERENCE TO COMMITTEE PART OF THE AGENDA SORRY AND OTHER
GENERAL MATTERS NOT ON TODAY'S AGENDA BUT MUST BE WITHIN THE
BOARD'S SUBJECT MATTER JURISDICTION.
>> WELCOME. ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOW THERE'S SO MANY LIES TOLD I COULDN'T PUT IT BETTER
THAN A DIVINE SENTENCE IS IN THE LIPS OF THE KING HIS
MOUTH TRANSGRESSES DID NOT IN JUDGMENT ADJUST, WAIT
AND BALANCE ARE THE LORDS ALL THE WEIGHTS OF THE BAG ARE HIS
WORK. IT IS AN ABOMINATION TO KINGS
AND YOU'RE ALL LIKE LITTLE KINGS RIGHT?
BUT IT SAYS HERE IT'S AN ABOMINATION TO KINGS TO COMMIT
WICKEDNESS. YES, BECAUSE THE THRONE IS
ESTABLISHED BY RIGHTEOUSNESS. RIGHTEOUS LIPS ARE THE DELIGHT
OF KINGS AND THEY LOVE HIM. THAT SPEAK IS RIGHT.
THE WRATH OF THE KING IS AS A MESSENGERS OF DEATH.
BUT A WISE MAN WILL PACIFY IT. PRIDE GOETH BEFORE DESTRUCTION
AND IN HAUGHTY SPIRIT BEFORE A FALL BETTER IT IS TO BE OF A
HUMBLE SPIRIT WITH THE LOWLY THAN TO DIVIDE THE SPOIL WITH
THE PROUD PRIDE IS ALWAYS SPOKEN OF IN A NEGATIVE MANNER
AND THE WORD OF GOD IT'S IT'S ALWAYS SPOKEN OF BUT IF YOU'RE
PROUD ABOUT SIN IF I'M PROUD ABOUT BEING A LADIES MAN YOU
KNOW I SHOULD BE ASHAMED OF BEING A LADIES MAN IF I WAS A
LADIES MAN AND YOU SHOULD BE ASHAMED IF YOU'RE A HOMOSEXUAL
,GOD CONDEMNS IT. IT DOESN'T MEAN YOU CANNOT BE
FORGIVEN BUT IT DOES MEAN THAT GOD GOD CONDEMNS IT.
THERE HAVE BEEN PEOPLE THAT USED TO BE HOMOSEXUALS, YOU
KNOW, AND THEN THEY GOT SAVED. >> I USED TO PREACH WITH THE
GUY AT U.C. BERKELEY. WHAT'S HIS NAME?
HE WAS A MANAGER OF A GAY BAR AND HE BECAME A CHRISTIAN.
I FORGOT THE GUY'S NAME BUT JESUS IS COMING SOON.
HE REALLY IS. WHEN TRUMP MADE HIS EASTER
PROFESSION THAT WAS AFTER 360 SABBATICAL CYCLES AND 360
MONTHS FROM THE START OF THE TIMES OF THE GENTILES THAT
JESUS DEATH AND RESURRECTION WAS THE GREATEST EVENT
IN HISTORY AND IT WAS HIS COMING SOON CALL OUT TO HIM
TODAY. >> THANK YOU, MARK.
LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
>> I HAVE A HANDOUT. WE'LL COME AND COLLECT THAT
FROM YOU. >> GOOD AFTERNOON BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. FOR THE RECORD, MY NAME IS
CHRIS FORD KLEIN. I ALSO GO BY SERGEANT KLEIN OF
THE UNITED STATES MARINE CORPS. I JUST PASSED OUT A PORTION OF
A DOCUMENT THAT WAS SUBMITTED TO FEDERAL COURT AND I HAVE
UNTIL JULY 14TH 2025 TO FILE AN AMENDED CLAIM WITH SPECIFIC
INCIDENTS FOR EACH ONE OF THE FOUR QUESTIONS PAY PARTICULAR
ATTENTION TO QUESTIONS TWO AND THREE WHEN VIOLATIONS OF
THE GUIDELINES. HOWEVER, TODAY I'M ASKING THE
CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO TO JOIN FORCES FORCES
WITH ME IN A CLASS ACTION LAWSUIT AGAINST STATE SPONSORED
TERRORISM SO THAT THE VICTIMS IN SAN FRANCISCO CAN RECEIVE
FUNDS FROM CONGRESS FROM THE CONGRESS ENACTED BY STATUTE
FUND SET UP FOR US VICTIMS OF STATE SPONSORED TERRORISM SINCE
SAN FRANCISCO WAS VICTIMIZED FOR A VARIETY OF REASONS SUCH
AS POLITICIANS THAT REPRESENT SAN FRANCISCO BE IT AT THE
LOCAL, STATE AND FEDERAL LEVEL YOU HOST FLEET WEEK EVERY YEAR
THERE'S A LARGE VETERAN POPULATION AND THERE ARE STILL
A MILITARY PRESENCE IN OR AROUND SAN FRANCISCO TO INCLUDE
THE 23RD MARINES TRAVIS AIR FORCE BASE AND PILLAR POINT AIR
FORCE BASE THAT IS CURRENTLY BEING BEING USED FOR U.S. SPACE
FORCE AND SEVERAL OTHER UNITS. UNFORTUNATELY, THE DEADLINE FOR
THE SIXTH INSTALLMENT HAS PASSED.
I URGE EACH OF YOU IN THIS ROOM TO PARTNER AND JOIN FORCES SO
THAT THE VICTIMS CAN BE COMPENSATED AND SAN FRANCISCO
CAN GET ITS FAIR SHARE OF THE FUND.
THE DEADLINE JUST PASSED WAS ON JUNE 2ND, 2025 AND I PREVIOUSLY
PRESENTED PRIOR TO THAT DATE. I'M CONFUSED AND DISMAYED BY
SEVERAL WHO HAVE REFUSED TO MOVE ON THIS AT A MUCH QUICKER
PACE AS SAN FRANCISCO SUFFERS PERHAPS ONE OF ITS MOST
FINANCIAL DOWNFALLS IN HISTORY .
LET'S WORK TOGETHER SAN FRANCISCO NOT AGAINST EACH
OTHER AGAIN THERE'S GOING TO BE ANOTHER DATE BUT THAT DOESN'T
FIX YOUR BUDGET FOR THIS YEAR AND NEXT YEAR.
IF IT WOULD HAVE BEEN SUBMITTED ON TIME THERE WOULDN'T HAVE
BEEN A BUDGET ISSUE THIS YEAR. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER I HAVE A HANDOUT
FOR EACH ONE OF YOUR BOARD SUPERVISORS.
I'M ASKING FOR THE POLICE DEPARTMENT TO HAVE FACIAL
RECOGNITION AND THE POLICE DEPARTMENT.
THAT'S WHAT THE LETTERS REGARDING IT'S FOR EVERY ONE OF
THEM. PLEASE CONTINUE.
>> YOU HAVE A MINUTE AND 35 SECONDS LEFT.
THAT'S ALL THAT'S ALL I HAVE TO SAY.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR LETTER TO THEM AND FOR YOUR TO READ IT
AND NOT JUST LOOK AT IT. TAKE IT REAL SERIOUS.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
WELCOME. >> GOOD AFTERNOON.
CITY SUPERVISORS AND FELLOW ESTEEMED NEUROSCIENTISTS.
IT'S PRIDE WEEK AS WE'RE ALL AWARE.
>> AND FOR ME AND MY FAMILY AND FOR MUCH OF SAN FRANCISCO,
THIS IS AS CLOSE TO A HOLY HOLIDAY AS WE'RE POSSIBLY GOING
TO GET. >> BUT IT'S DIRE TIMES.
AND RECENTLY THE FBI HAS SET UP A HOTLINE FOR ANYONE TO CALL
IN TO REPORT HEALTH CLINICS THAT MIGHT BE HARMING CHILDREN
BY QUOTE PERFORMING GENITAL MUTILATION.
NOW THIS IS A THINLY VEILED ATTEMPT AT ANTI-TRANS
PROPAGANDA SPECIFICALLY ANTI GENDER AFFIRMING CARE
PROPAGANDA. >> IT'S A VILE ACT.
NOW READING THE WRITING ON THE WALL UCSF, STANFORD AND THE
GENDER CONFIRMING CENTER HERE RIGHT HERE HAVE ALL CEASED
PROVIDING GENDER AFFIRMING CARE FOR ANYONE UNDER 19.
THAT HAPPENED THIS WEEK NOT TO BE UNDONE AN ACTS OF ABJECT
COWARDICE OUR MAYOR SOMEHOW EITHER ACCIDENTALLY BUT VERY
LIKELY PURPOSEFULLY DID NOT INCLUDE THE TRANS FLAG IN THE
PRIDE FLAG RAISING CEREMONY AT CITY HALL.
NOW THIS IS THE FIRST TIME THAT THIS HAS HAPPENED SINCE I CAN
REMEMBER. WE HAVE LOTS OF PHOTOGRAPHIC
EVIDENCE SHOWING THE TRANS FLAG RIGHT THERE BEHIND EVERY
MAYOR SPEECH FOR AS LONG AS I CAN REMEMBER.
THAT DID NOT HAPPEN THIS YEAR. IT'S NOT SURPRISING FOR A
CONSERVATIVE MAYOR WHO IS COOPERATING WITH ICE, BUT IT IS
QUITE FRANKLY A SURPRISE FOR THIS CITY.
NOW YOUR JOB AS LEGISLATURES AS A LEGISLATIVE BRANCH OF THIS
GOVERNMENT AND I CAN'T BELIEVE I HAVE TO TELL YOU THIS BUT I
DO YOUR JOBS IS TO CHECK THE MAYOR'S EXECUTIVE POWER.
IT IS NOT TO STAND BEHIND HIM IN SOCIAL MEDIA POSTS SMILING
LIKE YOU'RE HIS PERSONAL ASSISTANT READY TO DO HIS
BIDDING. HE'S NOT YOUR CONSTITUENCY.
WE ARE THE PEOPLE OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> AH, IT'S TUESDAY PRIDE MARCH IS SUNDAY.
>> THE TRANS MARCH IS FRIDAY. I EXPECT AND I HOPE THAT
SOMEWHERE IN OR OUTSIDE OF CITY HALL THE PRIDE FLAG AND THE
TRANS. >> RIGHT.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS ZACHARY FRIEL.
>> I'M WITH SAM CAN AND I'M AD5 RESIDENT.
YESTERDAY THE BUDGET AND APPROPRIATIONS COMMITTEE
HEARD FROM HUNDREDS OF SAN FRANCISCANS OPPOSING THE
DEVASTATING CUTS TO OUR CITY'S SOCIAL SAFETY NET.
THE MAYOR HAS CHOSEN TO BALANCE THE BUDGET BY SLASHING
ESSENTIAL SERVICES LIKE LEGAL AID, WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT,
FOOD BANKS AND HOMELESSNESS SERVICES FOR FAMILIES
AND TRANSITIONAL AGED YOUTH. >> AT THE SAME TIME, SOME OF
THE RICHEST CORPORATIONS IN THE CITY NAMELY AIRBNB, UBER
AND LYFT HAVE SUED THE CITY FOR OVER $400 MILLION, PROMPTING
THE CITY COMPTROLLER TO PUT HUNDREDS OF MILLIONS OF DOLLARS
INTO A LITIGATION RESERVE. THAT MONEY COULD BE COVERING
ALL OF THE LAYOFFS AND ALL OF THE CUTS TO OUR SERVICES
IN THIS BUDGET SEVERAL TIMES OVER.
WHY SHOULD OUR COMMUNITIES HAVE TO SUFFER BECAUSE OF THEIR
GREED? BILLIONAIRES AND CORPORATIONS
NEED TO PAY THEIR FAIR SHARE. THEY GOT RICH ON OUR BACKS.
THEY SHOULD NOT BE ABLE TO HOLD OUR TAX DOLLARS HOSTAGE.
>> WHOEVER OUR CITY IS PREVENTED FROM PASSING A WEALTH
TAX ON THOSE WHO HAVE EXPLOITED OUR LABOR, FLIPPED OUR HOMES
AND DISPLACED OUR COMMUNITY MEMBERS TO GET RICH.
WE SUPPORT SUPERVISORS CHEN CHAN WALTON AND FIELDER'S
RESOLUTION AND CALL UPON OUR REPRESENTATIVES IN SACRAMENTO.
ASSEMBLY MEMBER MATT HANEY, ASSEMBLY MEMBER CATHERINE
STEFANI AND SENATOR SCOTT WIENER TO PASS LEGISLATION THAT
WILL ALLOW LOCAL JURISDICTIONS LIKE OURS TO PASS A WEALTH TAX.
>> BILLIONAIRES AND CORPORATIONS NEED TO PAY
THEIR FAIR SHARE AND WE NEED TO REDISTRIBUTE THE WEALTH TO OUR
COMMUNITIES. THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT
SPEAKER. >> GOOD AFTERNOON.
MY NAME IS MARY TRAMMELL AND I WAS HERE IN EARLY MAY TO
DISCUSS WHY I HAVEN'T GOTTEN MY SETTLEMENT FROM THE CITY.
>> I USED TO WORK FOR THE HUMAN RIGHTS COMMISSION.
>> HI, MR. WALTON. I KNOW YOU REPRESENT MY
DISTRICT. MA'AM, PLEASE ADDRESS YOUR
COMMENTS TO THE BOARD AS A WHOLE.
>> I JUST SPOKE TO HIM. THAT'S ALL.
I KNOW HE'S A PART OF THE BOARD AS YOU ARE AND I HAVE NOT BEEN
PAID. I WAS IT WAS SETTLED
IN DECEMBER OF LAST YEAR. THE LAST TIME MY ATTORNEY WOULD
SPEAK TO ME WAS IN EARLY MARCH AND HE TOLD ME THAT BEFORE I
WOULD GET SETTLED THAT THE BOARD, THE SUPERVISORS AND THE
MAYOR YOUR CASE HAS TO GO BEFORE THEM.
NOW THERE'S THREE OTHER COWORKERS OF MINE THAT WAS
FIRED FROM THE HUMAN RIGHTS COMMISSION AND THEY DIDN'T WAIT
NO TEN NO SEVEN MONTHS. AND I'M HERE TO SAY THAT I HAD
A GOOD EXPERIENCE WORKING FOR THE CITY.
BUT YOU NEED TO TAKE A CLOSE LOOK AT WHO YOU HIRE FOR
DIRECTORS AND MANAGERS BECAUSE THOSE PEOPLE ARE NOT ON THE
SAME WAVELENGTH AS YOU. THEY WANT YOU TO DO WHAT THEY
WANT YOU TO DO. THEY DON'T WANT YOU TO OBEY THE
RULES AND REGULATIONS. AND I'M AN OLD FARM GIRL.
>> WE CROP TOBACCO. YOU HAD ONE WAY TO DO IT
AND THAT WAS RIGHT. >> WITH THESE CITY MANAGERS
AND DIRECTORS THEY ARE. >> THEY ARE LASCIVIOUS, SNEAKY
AND I WAS HERE A MONTH AGO. THE LADY IN THE PINK OVER THERE
IS THE ONE THAT HAD SOMEONE TO GET MY PHONE NUMBER
AND PERSONAL INFORMATION EMAIL AND SO FORTH.
>> I HAVEN'T HEARD FROM NOBODY. I WENT DOWN TO MY LAWYER'S
OFFICE WITH CITY HE I DON'T KNOW IF HE WAS IN THERE OR NOT
KNOCKED ON HIS DOOR. HE DIDN'T ASK TWICE THOUGH NOT
IT WAS LUCK. >> NOW WHO DO I NEED TO TALK
TO? WHO CAN I TALK TO?
WILL SOMEBODY TELL ME WHAT THE IS GOING ON?
>> I DON'T WANT TO HAVE TO GO TO CHANNEL SEVEN.
>> I HAVE SOME INFORMATION FOR YOU IF YOU'LL JUST STEP OVER TO
THE. THE LADY IN THE PINK DID THAT
IN EARLY MAY AND I HOPE YOU CAN GET BACK TO ME.
>> I HAVE INFORMATION FOR YOU. PLEASE.
THANK YOU. >> LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT
SPEAKER PLEASE. >> CAN YOU PRINT OUT THAT
SOMETHING ON YOUR WAY TO HEAR AIRWAVES IS YOURS?
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT. IT'S YOUR WAIT.
>> YOU'RE NOT AMERICAN. YOU'RE WHITE.
THIS IS THE WARM WELCOME YOU'LL RECEIVE FROM DIANA DEL DELGADO
AND FELLOW EMPLOYEES OF SIMCOE RESTAURANTS AT PIER 39.
IF YOU'RE NOT PRIVY TO BEING A FOREIGN NATIONAL OFF OUR OWN
OUR OWN BEING CITIZENS. >> LET ME ASK COULD I MAKE SUCH
A STATEMENT WITHOUT BEING CHARGED WITH A HATE CRIME?
COULD I MAKE SUCH A STATEMENT AND RETAIN MY EMPLOYMENT?
COULD I MAKE SUCH A STATEMENT AND NOT BE DEFINED A FASCIST?
TO BE CLEAR I AM FOR INTEGRATION BUT WHAT I'M NOT
FOR IS FOR FOREIGN CITIZENS OFF OUR OWN WHETHER THAT BE BY
DENIAL OF WAGES, STEALING OUR JOBS OR MURDERING US WITH DRUGS
WHILE HOLDING US TO STANDARDS THEY DO NOT FOLLOW THEMSELVES.
TO ANYONE FOR REPARATIONS FOR DEAD ANCESTORS THEY NEVER KNEW.
DON'T FORGET MINE FOR BEING STRANGLED FOR 35 MINUTES TO
THEN BE CHARGED WITH CRIMINAL DAMAGE TO PROPERTY AND SPEND
FOUR MONTHS IN CUSTODY FOR TAKING DOWN A CURTAIN WITH ON
IT. AMONG THE OTHER COUNTLESS
CRIMES COMMITTED BY THE OF EVERY RACE THAT MAKES
EVERYTHING A RACE ISSUE INSTEAD OF A MUTUAL RESPECT ISSUE.
MISS CHEN, YOU TODAY ABOUT OUR RIGHTS BEING TAKEN AWAY BY THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT. WHAT ABOUT THE CITY GOVERNMENT?
ARE YOU LIVING WITH STAPLED TO YOUR WALL?
MS. CHEN WELL MY ASIAN LANDLORD DEFINES ME AS A FREE MAN.
CAN WE CUT OFF HIS ADDRESS AS I'M DENIED DUE WAGES SEXUALLY
ASSAULTED AT WORK AND LAUGHED AT AS I'M ASKED IF I WANT TO GO
BACK TO JAIL? >> ARE YOU ALL LIVING WITH
STAPLED TO YOUR WALLS? WE'VE GOT AN $840 MILLION
POLICE BUDGET WITH MORE THAN THREE QUARTERS OF THOSE
OFFICERS NOT BEING RESIDENTS OF SAN FRANCISCO.
HERE'S ALL OF OUR MONEY. PLEASE DON'T US OFF.
I THINK WE'VE SEEN HOW GREAT THAT IDEOLOGY HAS WORKED OUT
DESPITE THE PUBLIC HEALTH DEPARTMENT HAVING A $3.2
BILLION BUDGET DURING MY MOST RECENT INCARCERATION I
WITNESSED MULTIPLE INDIVIDUALS REMAINING WITH IN THEIR PANTS
FOR A WEEK AT A TIME. >> SPEAKERS TIME'S EXPIRED.
SECURITY AND MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONALS WALKING BY AS THE
NEXT SPEAKER PLEASE. THE REALITY IS THEY DON'T CARE
. THEY DON'T CARE BECAUSE THEY
DON'T LIVE HERE. THEY DON'T CARE WHO CITIZENS.
>> NEXT SPEAKER GREETINGS AND CITATIONS SAN FRANCISCO.
MY NAME IS SEAN SUNSHINE STRICKLAND DISTRICT LEADER.
SOMETIMES KNOWN AS THE SUPER GIRL OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> AND I JUST WANT TO TAKE A MOMENT OF TIME FOR US TO
REFLECT AND PRAY FOR THE GOOD PEOPLE HERE IN THE CITY.
ALL OF YOU AND PLEASE JOIN ME FOR ABOUT 10S OF SILENCE.
>> MY MESSAGE IS TO DONALD TRUMP THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES OF AMERICA. >> YOU CLAIM TO BE A PERSON WHO
BELIEVES IN UNITY AND PEACE. >> AND YOUR ACTIONS AND YOUR
WORDS REFLECT OTHERWISE. IF YOU WERE TRULY A PERSON OF
PEACE WHO HAD A GOD BE LOVE GREAT TO SPIRIT TO LOVE IN THE
SIDE OF YOUR HEART AND SOUL THEN YOU WOULD BE DOING THINGS
AND SAYING THINGS TO BRING PEOPLE TOGETHER NOT JUST A
UNITED STATES OF AMERICA BUT ALSO HELPING TO PAVE THE PATH
FORWARD TO A UNITED EARTH. THAT'S WHAT I BELIEVE IN.
I'M NOT SURE WHAT YOU BELIEVE IN.
YOU'VE BEEN GIVEN NOTHING BUT PAIN SUFFERING TO THE PEOPLE
WHEN YOU SHOULD BE GIVING LOVE .
>> LOVE IS THE FIRST THING THAT SHOULD COME OUT OF YOUR MOUTH.
>> I BELIEVE IN INFINITE DIVERSITY AND INFINITE
COMBINATIONS. I BELIEVE IN LOVE, RESPECT
AND UNDERSTANDING TO ALL HUMAN BEINGS.
AND I BELIEVE THAT EVERYONE IS CREATED EQUAL AND THAT EVERY
LIFE ALL LGBTQ AIR LIFE, ALL PEOPLE OF THE RAINBOW SHOULD BE
TREATED WITH LOVE, RESPECT AND UNDERSTANDING ON THE PLANET
EARTH. THANK YOU ALL.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER.
>> HI. >> MY NAME IS NOW ADC BOARD
MEMBER DIRECTOR OF HIGHER EDUCATION.
>> I JUST WANT TO SPEAK TO THE SUPERVISORS INVOLVED WITH THE
THE BUDGET COMMITTEE. >> YOU KNOW WHO YOU ARE AND AND
MEETING AND ABOUT AND TO US AS WELL AS THE 2016 VOTERS VOTED
FOR A FREE CITY COLLEGE AND IS THAT SO?
WELL LIKE TWO YEARS LATER 2019 A BUDGET WAS WE VOTED TO HAVE
TEN YEARS OF CITY COLLEGE FREE AND SO AS PROMISED WE SUPPOSED
TO HAVE CITY CARS SUPPOSED TO BE FREE AND THAT WE ARE
SUPPOSED TO HAVE THE 40 MILLION I BELIEVE IN 20 2425 BUT WE
ONLY GOT HALF OF THAT. AND THAT IS IS PROBLEM IS THAT
WILL GET LIKE 7.2 BUT IT GOT UP TO I BELIEVE 9.3 BUT THAT IS
NOT ENOUGH IS LIKE WE FELL SHORT SO I JUST URGE YOU THAT
YOU CAN PUT MORE MONEY INTO TO PLAY FOR LIKE 17 OR 18 MILL
BECAUSE IT WAS HIS PROMISE WAS TO HAVE TEN YEARS OF FREE YOU
KNOW CITY COLLEGE AND HONOR. ON A PERSONAL NOTE I JUST WANT
TO KNOW I JUST WANT TO SAY THAT I LIVE IN NEW JERSEY.
>> I FROM SOUTH JERSEY AND I DID GO TO A COMMUNITY COLLEGE
AND IT REALLY SAVED ME AND I HAD NO IDEA THAT I HAD A
LEARNING DISABILITY SO THAT COLLEGE HELPED ME GAVE ME
CONFIDENCE TO THE POINT THAT I WAS ABLE TO TRANSFER TO ANOTHER
COLLEGE WHICH IS RUTGERS UNIVERSITY.
AND I JUST WANT TO SAY THAT I WISH I BE ABLE TO PAY FREE
IN MY TIME TO AND I'M NOT GOING TO MENTION MY A'S WERE BACK
IN THE DAY AND I JUST HOPE THAT THIS IS AN OPPORTUNITY FOR
ANYONE WHO WANTS THE EDUCATION BECAUSE YOU KNOW A MIND IS A
TERRIBLE THING IN WAYS WE HAD THIS OPPORTUNITY, WE VOTED FOR
IT, OUR TAXPAYER MONEY VOTED FOR THIS AND I I HOPE I HOPE
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS SO THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT SPEAKER PLEASE. OH, WE WAS HERE TO SPEAK ON
BEHALF OF OUR MOTHER. SHE JUST CAME UP TO YOU GUYS
AND HANDED OUT A LETTER. WE JUST WANTED TO READ PART OF
THE LETTER BASICALLY REGARDING INJUSTICE WHAT OUR BROTHER WHO
GOT KILLED LAST YEAR. WE JUST WANTED TO SEE IF IT'S
POSSIBLE TO PASS THE LAW FOR THE FOR FACIAL RECOGNITION.
>> BUT WE'LL READ YOU PART OF THE LETTER I AM WRITING TO
RESPECTFULLY URGE THE BOARD TO REVISIT AND RECONSIDER THE
CURRENT POLICY PROHIBITING THE USE OF FACIAL RECOGNITION
TECHNOLOGY BY LAW ENFORCEMENT IN SAN FRANCISCO WHO AS A
CONCERNED RESIDENT AND ADVOCATE FOR PUBLIC SAFETY.
I BELIEVE THAT WITH APPROPRIATE SAFEGUARDS THIS TECHNOLOGY CAN
BE A POWERFUL TOOL TO ENHANCE PUBLIC SAFETY, ASSIST
INVESTIGATIONS AND IMPROVE THE OVERALL EFFECTIVENESS OF POLICE
WORK WHEN USED RESPONSIBLY AND INTEREST IN TRANSPARENTLY
FACIAL RECOGNITION CAN HELP IDENTIFY SUSPECTS IN SERIOUS
CRIMES LOCATED LOCATE MISSING PERSONS, MISSING PEOPLE
AND PREVENT REAL TIME THREATS. MANY MAJOR CITIES AROUND THE
WORLD ARE SUCCESSFULLY INCORPORATING THIS TECHNOLOGY
INTO THEIR PUBLIC SAFETY STRATEGIES.
SAN FRANCISCO AS A PUBLIC LEADER IN BOTH TECH INNOVATIONS
AND CIVIL RIGHTS IS UNIQUELY POSITIONED TO SET THE STANDARD
FOR ETHICAL AND REGULATED USE. SO WE JUST WANTED TO BRING THAT
UP TO TO YOUR KNOWLEDGE, JUST BECAUSE SAN FRANCISCO DOES NOT
HAVE A FACIAL RECOGNITION THING FOR S.F. PD AND WE WERE JUST
WONDERING IF IT CAN GET WAIVED SO AND YEAH, THAT'S ALL WE
WANTED TO SAY FURTHER. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER OH YOU KNOW I LIKE
TO USE THE OVERHEAD AS I'VE GOT TO BE.
>> YESTERDAY I WAS THEY HAD THIS BROWN IF YOU COULD SPEAK
IT TO THEM LIKE YESTERDAY THEY HAD THEY HAD THE JUNETEENTH
AND I WAS MARCHING WITH THE MAYOR AND I MARCHED WITH THIS
PICTURE AS I BRING MY PICTURES HERE ALL THE TIME AND THE SFPD
,THE THE FIRE DEPARTMENT AND ALL OF THEM WE WERE ALL
MARCHING. SO IT WAS HARD FOR ME TO WALK
WITH THIS PICTURE. WE SAID JUNETEENTH WAS THE DAY
THAT FREEDOM BUT OUR CHILDREN ARE FREE.
OUR CHILDREN THAT ARE BEING MURDERED ON THE STREET AREN'T
FREE. >> I BRING THIS PICTURE OF MY
SON ALL THE TIME SAYING HE'S ONE OF THOSE CHILDREN.
MY SON WAS SHOT WITH A SEMIAUTOMATIC GUN.
30 ROUNDS OF BULLETS LEFT THAT GUN TO MY SON SAVING SOMEONE
ELSE'S LIFE. >> I COME HERE AND I SAID I
DON'T JUST FIGHT FOR MY CHILD BUT I THINK ABOUT ALL OTHER
MOTHERS AND FATHERS THAT ARE OUT THERE SUFFERING.
>> LOOK AT ALL THESE UNSOLVED HOMICIDES AND MURDERS THAT ARE
NOT SOLVED AND MOTHERS LIKE MYSELF AND OTHER MOTHERS ARE
STILL SUFFERING IN SILENCE. >> THIS IS THE PICTURE I WALK
WITH THE MAYOR AND AND ASKED HIM, YOU KNOW, I KNOW I BELIEVE
THAT HE UNDERSTANDS WHAT'S GOING ON WITH THOSE MOTHERS.
>> YOU KNOW, WHEN YOU GET AND YOU SAID ACCOUNTABILITY
SERVICE AND JUSTICE, THAT'S WHAT WE NEED NEXT MONTH WILL BE
HERE'S ANOTHER UNSOLVED HOMICIDE.
>> MATTIE SCOTT'S CHILD IS OVER HERE.
THIS IS WHAT THE PERPETRATORS LEFT ME A LIFELESS BODY.
THIS IS WHAT THEY LEFT ME. MY SON LAYING ON A GURNEY
LIFELESS. WHO WANTS TO SEE THAT THIS IS
WHAT I HAVE TO REMEMBER FOR THE REST OF MY LIFE.
>> HE WAS MY ONLY SON. WE SAID HATE CRIMES.
THIS WAS A HATE CRIME. >> I DON'T CARE ABOUT BLACK ON
BLACK CRIME. THIS WAS A HATE CRIME
AND MOTHERS LIKE MYSELF ARE STILL SUFFERING.
>> SOMETHING NEEDS TO BE DONE. I'M TIRED.
THANK YOU, MISS BROWN. NEXT SPEAKER, PLEASE.
OH, THANK. >> GOOD AFTERNOON.
MY NAME IS RICHARD. STEVE PETERSON TO THE BOARD
AND TO THE SUPERVISOR AT LARGE .
YOU KNOW I WANT TO APOLOGIZE. I USED TO BE A FAIRLY DECENT
EXTEMPORANEOUS SPEAKER WHEN I WAS A TRIAL ATTORNEY SINCE LONG
COVERED IN A COUPLE OF STROKES I'VE BEEN IN MY MIND HAS BEEN A
LITTLE WILD AND THAT'S WHY I'VE GOT OUT OF INTELLECTUAL
PROPERTY LAW AND NOW INTO FORTUNE TELLING BECAUSE FORTUNE
TELLING IS FAR MORE EASY AND PREDICTIVE AND IF YOU'VE
SEEN THE ADS ON TV FOR A LAWYERS APPARENTLY YOU CAN SAY
PRETTY MUCH WHAT YOU WANT AS A FORTUNE TELLER.
THERE ARE INNUMERABLE NUMBER OF RESTRICTIONS INCLUDING
ADVERTISING AND AND I DON'T KNOW HOW I'M SUPPOSED TO
CONTACT CLIENTS I MEAN PSYCHIC LEE IS THAT THE WAY BUT I'M THE
TOPIC I REALLY WANT TO TALK ABOUT IS PRODUCTIVE PROTESTS.
AS YOU KNOW LAST WEEK THIS MEETING WAS DISRUPTED FOR ABOUT
FOUR HOURS BY A SO-CALLED CITY SERVICE REP UNION SERVING THE
PUBLIC AND AS A PUBLIC MEMBER I ONLY CAN I ONLY CAN STAND AND I
ONLY CAN STAY SO LONG BEFORE ALL OF A SUDDEN I'M GOING TO
EITHER FALL DOWN. THAT'S WHY I WEAR A PROTECTIVE
MOTORCYCLE JACKET OR NOT SO PRODUCTIVE.
THAT'S NOT AN EXAMPLE OF JUST THE DISRUPTIVE NATURE OF THAT
PROTEST WAS NOT PRODUCTIVE AND THERE ARE OTHER WAYS OF
PRODUCTIVE PROTESTS IF YOU SEE IN THE STREETS CERTAINLY THE NO
KINGS THING WHY ARE WE WAVING MEXICAN FLAGS?
I JUST DON'T KNOW. >> THINGS ARE SO TOPSY TURVY.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS. THANK YOU FOR LETTING ME SPEAK
TODAY. MY NAME'S CURTIS BRADFORD
AND I'M JUST A TENDERLOIN RESIDENT AND I DO COMMUNITY
ORGANIZING IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD AND AND IN THE CITY AND BUT I
REALLY WASN'T EVEN HERE TODAY TO SAY ANYTHING.
I CAME FOR AN EVENT EARLIER BUT AFTER HEARING A COUPLE OF THE
COMMENTS TODAY I JUST FELT LIKE I WANTED TO GET UP AND SAY
SOMETHING TO THE FOLKS WHO ARE WATCHING WHICH IS MOST OF THE
FOLKS HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO ARE GOOD HEARTED FOLKS AND WE WE
CARE ABOUT EACH OTHER. WE LOVE EACH OTHER AND WE
SUPPORT EACH OTHER. THE TENDERLOIN, FOR EXAMPLE, IS
PROBABLY THE MOST DIVERSE FOR NINE SQUARE BLOCKS IN AMERICA.
WE HAVE EVERY CREED, EVERY RACE ,EVERY RELIGION YOU KNOW,
EVERY LANGUAGE. IT IS EVERY SEXUALITY, EVERY
ORIENTATION AND GENDER IDENTITY .
IT IS AN AMAZING COMMUNITY AND WE DEMONSTRATE REGULARLY
HOW WE CAN ALL LIVE TOGETHER, ENJOY IN PEACE AND SUPPORT EACH
OTHER. AND I JUST WANT FOLKS LISTENING
WHO MIGHT HAVE HEARD SOME CONTRADICTORY MESSAGES TODAY
THAT THAT YOU KNOW, YOU'RE WELCOME HERE.
>> WE LOVE YOU HERE. THE MAJORITY OF US HERE LOVE
YOU. YOU'RE A BEAUTIFUL PERSON.
I SEE YOU. YOU'RE BEAUTIFUL.
GOD SEES YOU. YOU'RE BEAUTIFUL.
AND I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW YOUR LOVED THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER WHAT HAPPENED TO
ANGELA? SHE JUST FLEW AWAY.
IT'S LIKE OKAY, LET'S NOT FAKE FOR SURE IS THAT INTELLIGENCE
KNOWS THAT PRIDE IS IS ENEMY FIRE, RIGHT?
>> YES. OKAY.
SUCH AS AFTER THAT THE STIGMATIZATION OF CALLS ON THIS
IT'S KIND OF ALMOST SURPRISING THAT YOU HAVEN'T TRIED YET A
BLACK RAMBO NEVER MIND. I'VE GOT MORE IMPORTANT TO SAY
ABOUT THIS 5G TOWERS. YES.
CONNECTED TO THE FACT THAT NO MATTER WHAT YOU CANNOT JUSTIFY
IT THEIR PRESENCE WHICH IS NEFARIOUS BY THE SAYING THAT IT
IS FOR HIGH SPEED INTERNET BECAUSE I SAID SEVERAL TIMES
BEFORE THAT SPEED IS DANGER. SO HIGH SPEED INTERNET MEANS NO
MATTER WHAT ARE YOU DANGER INTERNET CLEAR ENOUGH SO YES
NOW WHAT'S THE NEXT STAGE BECAUSE YOU HAVE NOW A ONE WEEK
TO START REMOVING MOST OF THESE 5G OR EVEN SIX I DON'T KNOW WHO
KNOWS THINGS THAT YOU DIDN'T ASK THE PEOPLE TO PUT ON.
>> I EXPLAINED THAT TO YOU LAST WEEK WHEN OKAY NO NEVER MIND.
>> HURRY UP. DON'T FORGET YOUR BREAKFAST
WITH YOUR ORANGE SIGNALIZATION FOR THE FAKE WORLD WORK ROADS
WORK SORRY THAT YOU PUT ON ABOUT THE COUNTRYSIDE TO PEACE
AGAINST WORRY EVERYBODY OF THIS INCLUDES YOUR YELLOW
FLUORESCENT YELLOW GLOBALISTS THE SIGNS THE PRETENDING TO
CARE ABOUT PEDESTRIANS OH ANYBODY ANYBODY ELSE.
WHEREAS IT'S EXACTLY THE OPPOSITE A HURRY UP YOUR OWN
INTELLIGENCE IS NATURALIZING ITSELF AS I SAID AND YOU MAKE
YOUR CONSPIRACY ABSOLUTELY OBVIOUS FOR EVERYONE.
CONGRATULATION. THAT'S ALL WE NEED.
HAVE A GOOD DAY. SEE YOU NEXT WHICH IS JULY 1ST.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. ARE THERE ANY OTHER MEMBERS OF
THE PUBLIC WHO WOULD LIKE TO ADDRESS THE BOARD DURING
GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT? >> PLEASE STEP UP.
ALL RIGHT, MR. PRESIDENT, PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED.
>> MADAM CLERK, I THINK WE WANT TO REOPEN ROLL CALL.
YES? >> SUPERVISOR WALTON ASKED TO
REOPEN ROLL CALL. THANK YOU SO MUCH, PRESIDENT
MADAM. AND AND THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
COLLEAGUES, I DO HAVE IN MEMORIAM FOR THIS MEETING.
IT IS WITH DEEP SORROW AND HEARTFELT RESPECT THAT WE
HONOR THE LIFE AND LEGACY OF QUEEN AISHA.
AFFECTIONATELY KNOWN AS AUNTIE JOHN IN A TRUE LIGHT AND LEADER
IN THE SAMOAN AND PACIFIC ISLANDER COMMUNITY, QUEEN AISHA
AINA WAS A BRIGHT SHINING STAR. BORN IN SOUTH SAN FRANCISCO,
SHE ATTENDED PARKWAY MIDDLE SCHOOL AND GRADUATED FROM SOUTH
SAN FRANCISCO HIGH SCHOOL. SHE IS CLOSE TO HER HEART.
HER FAMILY, HER FAITH AND HER SECOND HOME.
THE SAMOAN COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT CENTER.
>> FOR 23 YEARS QUEEN AISHA DEVOTED HERSELF TO AC DC AND TO
THE VISITATION VALLEY AND SUNNYDALE NEIGHBORHOODS.
HER PASSION FOR UPLIFTING THE NEXT GENERATION WAS UNMATCHED
AND SHE WORKED TIRELESSLY TO ENSURE OUR YOUTH WERE EMBRACED
WITH LOVE GUIDED BY CULTURE AND INSPIRED BY HER
UNFORGETTABLE JOY. QUEEN AISHA EMBODY HER CULTURE
IN EVERY WAY THROUGH SONG, THROUGH DANCE AND THROUGH HER
UNWAVERING COMMITMENT TO PRESERVING AND CELEBRATING
PACIFIC ISLANDER TRADITIONS. >> ANYONE WHO WALK THE HALLS OF
AC DC KNEW WHEN THE QUEEN WAS PRESENT YOU COULD HEAR HER
SINGING CHURCH HYMNS WITH POWER AND GRACE FILLING THE SPACE
WITH SPIRIT AND SONG AT EVERY COMMUNITY EVENT.
QUEEN AISHA BROUGHT HER FULL AUTHENTIC SELF WITH PRIDE
AND CONFIDENCE. SHE DECLARED THE QUEEN IS HERE
AND THE ENTIRE ROOM WILL LIGHT UP IN RESPONSE.
>> SHE WAS A FORCE OF LOVE, WARMTH AND HOPE.
SHE CREATED SPACE FOR OUR YOUTH TO FEEL SEEN, SUPPORTED
AND VALUE. >> HER PASSING IS A TREMENDOUS
LOSS BUT HER LEGACY IS FOREVER. IT LIVES ON IN THE HEART OF AC
DC AND EVERY YOUNG PERSON SHE MENTORED AND IN THE STRENGTH OF
A COMMUNITY MADE BETTER BECAUSE SHE WAS PART OF IT.
>> FIRE FIGHTER. TELL A LAVA QUEEN THANK YOU FOR
YOUR SERVICE, YOUR SPIRIT AND YOUR UNSHAKABLE.
>> LONG LIVE THE QUEEN. THE REST I SUBMIT.
THANK YOU SO MUCH. >> SUPERVISOR WALTON.
THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. >> THANK YOU, SIR, FOR AS WELL
AND THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. LET'S GO TO OUR FOUR ADOPTION
OF THAT COMMITTEE REFERENCED AGENDA ITEMS 27 THROUGH 31
ITEMS 27 THROUGH 31 WERE INTRODUCED FOR ADOPTION BUT
WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE. A UNANIMOUS VOTE IS THEREFORE
REQUIRED FOR ADOPTION OF A RESOLUTION ON FIRST READING
TODAY. ALTERNATIVELY, A MEMBER MAY
REQUIRE A RESOLUTION ON FIRST READING TO GO TO COMMITTEE.
I'M GOING TO ASK THAT WE PULL 29 AND I DON'T SEE ANYONE ELSE
SO MADAM CLERK CAN YOU CALL THE ROLL ON THE REMAINING BALANCE
OF ITEMS ON ITEMS 27, 2830 AND 31?
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES SUPERVISOR WALTON HIGH WALTON
EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR AND ENGARDIO
AND GUARDIAN EYES SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER.
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD EYES SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HIGH
MANDEL MEN EYES SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR.
I AND SUPERVISOR SADR SADR EITHER ARE LEBANESE WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED AND THEN MADAM CLERK
CAN YOU PLEASE CALL ITEM 29 ITEM 29.
THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO CONDEMN ANTI-SEMITISM AND ALL FORMS OF
RACE AND RELIGION BASED VIOLENCE IN SAN FRANCISCO
AND TO REAFFIRM ITS COMMITMENT TO AN OPEN, INCLUSIVE AND SAFE
CITY THAT ACTIVELY OPPOSES ALL FORMS OF HATE INCLUDING THOSE
BASED ON RELIGION, ETHNICITY, RACE, SEX, NATIONAL ORIGIN,
IMMIGRATION STATUS, SEXUAL ORIENTATION AND GENDER IDENTITY
OR EXPRESSION AND DISABILITY. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
COLLEAGUES, I INTRODUCE THIS RESOLUTION LAST WEEK IN THE
WAKE OF A NUMBER OF RECENT ANTI-SEMITIC INCIDENTS LOCALLY
AND NATIONALLY. HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO WE'VE
SEEN THE REPEATED TARGETING AND HARASSMENT OF PROMINENT
JEWISH INDIVIDUALS, BUSINESSES AND INSTITUTIONS.
WE'VE SEEN BULLYING AND EVEN VIOLENT ASSAULTS ON JEWS OF NO
PARTICULAR PROMINENCE AT ALL IN THE UNITED STATES.
AT DIFFERENT TIMES IN OUR HISTORY IT HAS BEEN EASY FOR
AMERICAN JEWS TO IMAGINE THAT ANTI-SEMITISM IS NOT A THING
HERE. I CERTAINLY BELIEVE THAT
GROWING UP IN SAN FRANCISCO MY GRANDMOTHER HAD COME TO THE
UNITED STATES IN THE 50S BRINGING MY FATHER ACROSS THE
ATLANTIC ON A BOAT TO SURVIVOR OF A CONTINENT GONE GONE MAD.
>> SHE HAD SEEN ANTI-JEWISH HATE UP CLOSE AND HAD LOST MOST
OF HER FAMILY TO IT. BUT THAT WAS EUROPE IN A
DIFFERENT TIME. THAT KIND OF THING JUST
COULDN'T HAPPEN IN THIS COUNTRY .
>> THE IRISH WRITER CONOR CRUISE ORION DESCRIBED
ANTI-SEMITISM AS A LIGHT SLEEPER.
THAT OBSERVATION SEEMS PARTICULARLY RELEVANT TO THE
CURRENT MOMENT IN THIS COUNTRY WHERE HATREDS OF ALL KINDS ARE
ROUSING ON THE RIGHT AND THE LEFT.
THE UNITED STATES IN 2025 IS OF COURSE NOT EUROPE IN 1933 BUT
ANCIENT BIGOTRIES DO SEEM TO FIND A WAY TO ADAPT THEMSELVES
TO CHANGING TIMES. AND JEWS NOW DO KNOW FROM OUR
HISTORY THAT THOSE HATREDS LEFT UNCHECKED CAN DO UNIMAGINABLE
HARM. SO COLLEAGUES, I BELIEVE AT THE
VERY LEAST THIS IS A MOMENT FOR OUR BOARD OF SUPERVISORS TO
SPEAK UP ABOUT THIS PARTICULAR FORM OF HATRED, TO CONDEMN IT
AND RECOMMIT OURSELVES TO ENSURING THAT SAN FRANCISCO
CONTINUES TO BE A WELCOMING CITY FOR JEWS AND FOR ALL
PEOPLE. I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR YOUR
UNANIMOUS CO-SPONSORSHIP. I WANT TO THANK J CRC AND I
WANT TO THANK ESPECIALLY SUPERVISOR MELGAR FOR YOUR
INPUT ON LANGUAGE. >> AND I WANT TO THANK MELANIE
MATTHEW IN MY OFFICE FOR ALL OF HER WORK ON THIS.
AND I THINK WE CAN TAKE THAT ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED AND MADAM
CLERK, DO WE HAVE ANY IMPERATIVE AGENDA ITEMS?
>> THERE ARE NONE TO REPORT, MR. PRESIDENT.
>> THEN COULD YOU READ THE IN MEMORIAM?
YESTERDAY'S MEETING WILL BE ADJOURNED IN MEMORY OF THE
FOLLOWING BELOVED INDIVIDUAL. ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR WALTON
FOR THE LATE ASIA ANTIGEN INNER I THINK THAT BRINGS US TO THE
END OF OUR AGENDA. MADAM CLERK IS THERE ANY
FURTHER BUSINESS BEFORE US TODAY?
>> THAT CONCLUDES OUR BUSINESS FOR TODAY THEN WE ARE ADJOURNED